[MUSIC]
(音乐)
Stanford University,
斯坦福大学,
>> Welcome to Stanford CS193P,
> >欢迎来到斯坦福CS193P,
developing applications for iOS,
iOS应用程序开发,
It's winter of 2017,
这是2017年冬天,
This is lecture number 11 and
这是11号和讲座
today we're gonna do one gigantic demo,
今天我们要做一个巨大的演示,
Last time I made you suffer through basically doing
上次我让你遭受基本上做的
all slides,
所有幻灯片,
Now, you get to enjoy all demo for the whole time,
现在,你可以享受所有演示了整个时间,
And it's all gonna be about Core Data and applying all
都是会对核心数据和应用
the things that we learned in the last lecture into a demo,
我们在上节课学到的演示,
And then we'll be coming back to the slides, so
然后我们会回到幻灯片,
let me just give you a heads up of what's happening here,
让我给你一个头这里发生了什么,
On Friday, we have this other database mechanism for
上周五,我们有这个其他数据库的机制
storing data in iCloud,
在云存储数据,
I highly recommen this one, at our Friday section,
我强烈recommen这个,在我们周五部分,
normal place and time,
正常的地点和时间,
Monday's a holiday, so
周一的一个节日,所以
don't show up here on Monday cuz I won't be here,
周一没有出现在这里因为我不会在这里,
And then next Wednesday, I'll be going over the final
然后下个星期三,我将会在最后
project requirements, including the rubric, and
项目需求,包括标题和
also we'll be doing the topic, autolayout,
我们也会做主题,自动布局,
Now, your assignment five has been
现在,作业5
posted already, and it's due one
已经发布了,它是由于一个
week from today before lecture,
星期从今天开始演讲之前,
So here's Smashtag from last week,
这是Smashtag从上周,
Remember we have this one MVC where we type in a search
记得我们有这一个MVC输入一个搜索
string, #Stanford or whatever else,
字符串,#斯坦福或者其他,
and it pulls down a bunch of tweets,
这一群推拉下,
Now we're just gonna add another MVC,
现在,我们要添加另一个MVC,
a core data driven MVC,
一个核心数据驱动的MVC,
And when this MVC is gonna show all the Twitter users who
当这个MVC会显示所有的Twitter用户
tweeted all the tweets that are showing in this MVC
在推特上的所有微博显示MVC
right here,
在这里,
So, if you type a certain search term like #Stanford,
所以,如果你输入一个特定的搜索词像#斯坦福大学,
Stanford gets a bunch of tweets,
斯坦福大学被一群微博,
And then there's gonna be a button on this MVC,
然后会有一个按钮在这个MVC,
we're gonna put it up in the title bar,
我们要把它的标题栏,
we're gonna show you how to do that as well,
我们会告诉你怎么做,
And you're gonna click that button,
你会点击那个按钮,
It's gonna bring a new MVC with all the users, and
它会带来一个新的MVC的用户,和
we'll also put in there how many times,
我们也会把多少次,
how many tweets they tweeted,
多少微博发微博
When we do that, we're only gonna be looking at the tweets
当我们这样做,我们只会看微博
that are in this result, this search result right here,
在这个结果,这个搜索结果,
or that have ever come from typing this search term,
或者曾经来自输入搜索词,
All right, so this is all gonna be core data,
好吧,这是所有核心数据,
So we need core data in our app,
所以我们需要核心数据在我们的应用程序,
When we built Smashtag we didn't click use core data, so
当我们建立Smashtag没有点击使用核心数据,
we're gonna have to go through the procedures that I talked
我们要办理的手续,我说
about last time for adding core data to our app,
关于上次的核心数据添加到我们的应用程序,
And we're gonna do that by creating a dummy
我们要做的,通过创建一个假
app right here,
应用程序在这里,
Let's go to New > Project,
让我们去新的>项目时,
So we're gonna create a dummy project,
所以我们要创建一个虚拟项目,
you can call this project anything you want,
这个项目你可以叫任何你想要的,
I'm gonna call it Foo,
我要叫它Foo,
Just make sure that Use Core Data is clicked right there,
确保使用核心数据点击,
We can put it anywhere we want cuz we're just gonna turn
我们可以在任何地方把它因为我们要
around and delete it in a moment,
删除它,
And you can see that it has created this dummy project,
你可以看到它已经创造了这个虚拟项目,
And all we're really interested in here is
和所有我们真正感兴趣的
the code from the AppDelegate that does core data,
的代码在AppDelegate核心数据,
You can see that this AppDelegate imports CoreData,
你可以看到这个AppDelegate CoreData进口,
Now we haven't talked about the AppDelegate, and we will,
现在我们还没有谈到在AppDelegate,我们将
It's part of the application lifecycle,
这是应用程序生命周期的一部分,
But, for now,
但是,就目前而言,
all we need to know is that we're gonna go down here and
我们需要知道的是,我们要在这里
get this stuff or core data,
得到这个东西或核心数据,
you recognize this from the slides,
你认识这个幻灯片,
And notice also this applicationWillTerminate calls
注意这个applicationWillTerminate调用
saveContext,
SaveContext is one of the Core Data methods that you get for
SaveContext是核心数据的方法得到
So I'm actually gonna select that as well as all the rest
所以我要选择,以及所有的休息
free here,
在这里,自由
of this stuff is marked Core Data right there,
这些被标记的核心数据,
And I'm just gonna copy it,
我要复制它,
I'm gonna close this project cuz I don't need it,
我要关闭这个项目因为我不需要它,
And I'm gonna go over to the AppDelegate in my Smashtag
我要去在AppDelegate Smashtag
right here,
在这里,
And you can see it doesn't import core data right there
你可以看到它不导入核心数据
at the top,
在顶部,
Nor does applicationWillTerminate call
applicationWillTerminate也不叫
SaveContext, nor does it have any of other stuff down there,
SaveContext,也没有任何其他的东西,
So I'm just gonna take that code and paste in here,
所以我要把代码粘贴在这里,
And this code is generic, it works in all applications,
这代码是通用的,适用于所有应用程序,
The only thing that's specific about it is this string right
唯一的具体这个字符串是正确的
here, which tells you the data model, the thing that
,告诉你数据模型,的事情
describes the schema of your object or in a database,
描述了对象的模式或数据库中,
Now you notice we have an error right here, that's
现在你注意到我们有一个错误,这是
because it doesn't recognize NSPeristentContainer,
因为它不认识NSPeristentContainer,
Because NSPeristentContainer is in a different framework
因为NSPeristentContainer是在一个不同的框架
than UIKit, it's in CoreData,
比UIKit CoreData,
So every time you're using CoreData in a swift file,
所以每次你使用CoreData在迅速文件中,
you need to import CoreData or it won't recognize in this
你需要进口CoreData也不会承认这一点
managed object or any of the other symbols from core data,
管理对象或任何其他符号的核心数据,
So that's one thing we have to do that we use Core Data
这是我们必须做的一件事,我们使用核心数据
The other one is actually create the data model itself,
另一个是实际创建数据模型本身,
button did,
按钮,
And that we do with File > New > File, so
我们与File > New >文件,
I'm gonna go File > New > File,
点击File > New >文件,
And we, normally we're picking things up here but we're gonna
我们通常我们捡东西但我们会
scroll down to where it says Core Data and pick Data Model,
向下滚动到核心数据和数据模型,
We don't want Mapping Model, we want Data Model,
我们不想映射模型,数据模型,
This is just gonna be that thing where we describe all
这只是将那件事我们描述所有的地方
our entities and attributes,
我们的实体和属性,
And we can call it anything we want,
我们可以叫它任何我们想要的,
Just to be kind of different I'm gonna call it Smash,
只是有点不同的我要叫它打碎,
That's gonna be the name of my Data Model,
这是要我的名字数据模型,
And I'm not gonna put in Supporting Files,
和我不会放在支持文件,
I'm gonna put it in Smashtag in a higher,
我要把它放在Smashtag更高,
this level up here and click Create,
这个水平并单击创建、
And here it is,
是这样的,
You can probably recognize this, right?
你可以认识到这一点,对吧?
This is our entities and attributes,
这是我们的实体和属性,
We haven't put any of them in there,
我们还没有把其中的任何一个,
Now, since I call this Smash and not Foo,
现在,既然我称之为粉碎而不是Foo,
I've to go back to my AppDelegate and
我回到AppDelegate和
change this Foo string in here to be Smash,
改变这个字符串Foo被粉碎,
So I've pretty much now reproduced everything that
所以我现在几乎复制一切
the use core data button would do,
使用核心数据按钮,
The only difference would be the use core data would have
唯一不同的是使用核心数据
called my xcdatamodeld file,
叫我xcdatamodeld文件,
It would have called it Smashtag,
它会称之为Smashtag,
cuz that's the name of my app, but I like to call it Smash,
因为这是我的程序的名字,但是我喜欢叫它打碎,
All right, so now that we have this nice data model file,
好了,现在我们有这个很好的数据模型文件,
let's go ahead and create our schema,
让我们创建模式,
Now, I'm gonna do this really quick because I already showed
现在,我要做这个很快,因为我已经显示
you how to do all this which you can just watch it
你如何做这一切,你可以看它
happening real fast,
发生的很快,
I'm not gonna show you anything that I didn't show
我不会告诉你任何我没有展示
you in the last lecture,
你的最后一课,
I'm gonna start by adding an entity down here at
下面我要开始通过添加一个实体
All right, this entity I'm going to rename it,
好吧,这个实体我要重命名它,
the bottom,
底部,
And I'm gonna do tweets and Twitter users cuz I'm gonna
我要做微博和推特用户因为我要
have that table that follows Twitter users,
那张桌子,Twitter用户,
But obviously those Twitter users are determined by
但显然这些Twitter用户是由
a bunch of tweets, so those are two entities I need,
一群微博,所以我需要这两个实体,
So let's put Tweet here first, and
所以我们先把推特这里,
we'll add attributes for the tweet,
我们将添加属性的微博,
I'm gonna add them by clicking this little plus right here,
我要把它们通过点击这个小加在这里,
So we have the Text Attribute which is a String,
我们是一个字符串的文本属性,
We have our tweets, what if we search for
我们有微博,如果我们在搜寻什么
#Stanford twice in a row?
#斯坦福连续两次吗?
We might get the same tweet back,
我们可能会得到同样的推回来,
And we want our database to have unique tweets,
我们希望我们的数据库有独特的微博,
we don't wanna every time we search we're getting more and
我们不想每次我们搜索我们获得更多
more of the same tweet in there,
更多相同的微博,
So I need some sort of unique
所以我需要某种独一无二的
attribute in my database which is gonna a string,
属性在我的数据库是一个字符串,
Luckily, the Twitter info that comes in the Twitter
幸运的是,Twitter的Twitter信息
framework, it has a unique identifier in there for
框架,它有一个惟一的标识符
tweets so it'll be really easy to set that,
微博所以就很容易,
And I'm not gonna use this but for
我不会使用这个但
example, if I wanted a created attribute it would be a date,
例子,如果我想要一个创建属性,那将是一个日期,
I would just click Date,
我就点击日期,
I'm putting this in here cuz I just wanna show you what
我将在这里因为我想告诉你什么
it's like to set a date in code,
就像在代码中设定一个日期,
This looks slightly tricky,
这看起来有点棘手,
So I'm gonna add another, or
所以我要添加另一个,或
actually we could look here in the Editor Style,
实际上我们可以看这里的编辑风格,
So this is the exact same thing here in
这是相同的东西在这里
the Editor Style,
编辑风格,
When you're in Editor Style,
当你在编辑风格,
you're almost always gonna have your inspector
你几乎总是会有你的检查员
open right here so that you can click on things and
打开这里,这样您就可以点击,
change their types and things like that,
改变他们的类型和类似这样的事情,
I'm gonna create another entity here and it's going to
我要创建另一个实体,它会
be our Twitter user, I'm gonna call that Twitter user,
是我们的Twitter用户,我要调用Twitter用户,
And notice when I move these around,
注意当我移动这些,
it moves it around whatever other entities there are,
它在任何其他实体,
And I'm gonna be connecting these two and
我要这两个和连接
creating a relationship, and you're gonna see it's gonna
创建一个关系,你会看到它
keep drawing it as we draw there,
保持它画成画,
So let's add some attributes here,
让我们添加一些属性,
So I'm gonna click Add Attribute,
所以我要点击添加属性,
Sorry,
对不起,
It's not deleting, let's go back to Editor Style here,
不是删除,让我们回到编辑风格,
By the way, I do notice sometimes that when selecting
顺便说一下,我确实注意到有时,当选择
things, it's not always that great,
事情,这并不总是很好,
it doesn't do that great a job,
没有伟大的工作,
I'm not sure what it is about the data modeler that makes it
我不确定这是什么使得它的数据建模师
that way, but you'll click on something,
这样,但是你会点击,
and it doesn't click on that thing,
也不会点击它,
it clicked the entity or something else,
它点击实体或别的东西,
So there is an example where I was clicking on that
这是一个例子,我是点击
attribute, but it wouldn't let me delete it,
属性,但它不让我删除它,
Here I have Twitter user chosen,
在这里我有推特用户选择,
hopefully add attribute,
希望添加属性,
Yes, it adds it to the Twitter user,
是的,它将其添加到Twitter用户,
The only attributes I'm gonna have on my Twitter user
唯一我要对我的Twitter用户属性
are the handle, that's your @whatever, and then your name,
处理,这是你的@whatever,然后你的名字,
And those are both going to be strings, so
这些都是字符串,所以
we'll go over here and make this be of type string,
我们去这里,这是string类型的,
And we'll also make the handle be type string,
和我们也会使处理字符串类型,
So that's it for the attributes,
这是它的属性,
And the only thing we have left to do is the relationship
和我们唯一剩下要做的就是关系
between these two,
在这两个之间,
And I'm gonna hold down Ctrl and
我要按住Ctrl和
drag between the two right here,
拖两个在这里,
And you see it creates a new relationship on both sides,
你看到它创建一个新的关系双方,
But we don't want that,
但是我们不希望这样,
the Twitter user here, this relationship is the tweets
这里的Twitter用户,这种关系是tweet
that this Twitter user has tweeted,
这个推特用户写道:,
And for the tweet, this relationship is the tweeter,
微博,这种关系是推特,
the person who tweeted it,
的人在推特上,
This tweets relationship right here we know is a "too many"
这个微博关系我们知道是“太多”
relationship because a Twitter user gonna have multiple
因为Twitter用户将有多个的关系
tweets,
微博,
That's why get the little double arrow there,
这就是为什么小双箭头,
That's our entire data model that we need now,
这就是我们现在需要我们整个数据模型,
For your homework assignment,
你的家庭作业,
you're gonna need more things in here,
你需要更多的事情在这里,
This is not gonna be sufficient to the task, so
这是任务,不会足以
you're gonna have to add some more stuff,
你需要添加一些更多的东西,
But for our simple example, this is all we need,
但是对于我们的简单的例子,这是我们所需要的,
Now, we know that we wanna access all this stuff,
现在,我们知道我们想要访问所有这些东西,
not using value in for key and set value for key,
没有使用价值为键,键和设置值
We wanna have subclasses,
我们想有子类,
a subclass called TwitterUser and a club,
一个子类TwitterUser和一个俱乐部,
subclass called Tweet,
子类称为Tweet,
And we want them to have the vars for
我们希望他们有var
all of these attributes and relationships,
所有这些属性和关系,
And so, we need that code to be generated,
所以,我们需要生成代码,
And the way we do that is we just select the answer to,
我们的方法是我们选择的答案,
you see I've selected Tweet right here, entity Tweet,
你看到我选定的Tweet,实体推特,
And you go down here to Codegen, and
你去下面Codegen,
this says, by default, Class Definition,
这个说,默认情况下,类定义,
That means that it's done it,
这意味着完成它,
it has generated a class called tweet, and
它生成一个类称为tweet,
it's gonna work with all the vars in relationship,
它会处理所有的var的关系,
But that's not actually what we want,
但实际上这并不是我们想要的,
We want to pick this one, where it only
我们想选这个,它只在哪里
creates an extension to tweet that add to the vars stuff,
创建一个扩展tweet添加到,var的东西,
That's because we wanna write the class tweet and
这是因为我们想要写类微博和
be able to put our own code in there,
能够把我们自己的代码,
It's very common to one will write the class herself
是很常见的一个将编写自己的类
the main class,
主类,
But you still want the var magic, so
但你仍然希望var魔法,所以
you want those extensions in there,
你想要这些扩展,
Another thing that I didn't really mention in lecture, and
另一件事我没有提到的讲座,和
really, I don't think really matters unless you're in
真的,我不认为真正重要的,除非你在
a workspace like we are, you know, we have Twitter and
一个工作区,你知道,我们有Twitter和
smash dot org space, is this module name right here,
打碎点组织空间,这里的模块名称,
If you don't have anything in here,
如果你在这里,没有什么
then it's gonna use a global namespace for these classes,
然后它会使用这些类的全局名称空间,
like tweet, so it's gonna call the class tweet,
喜欢微博,所以它会调用类微博,
But actually, we already have a Twitter,tweet, and
但实际上,我们已经有一个推特,推特,
now we're gonna have Smashtag,tweet,
现在我们要有Smashtag,推特,
So we want to change this to be current product module,
所以我们要改变这是当前的产品模块,
So don't forget this,
所以不要忘记这个,
Wake up, if you're not paying attention,
醒来,如果你不注意,
If you don't put this right here,
如果你不放这里,
you're likely to get tons of errors,
你可能会得到大量的错误,
All kinds of conflicting class names,
各种冲突的类名,
and even if your app builds, it won't run,
即使你的应用构建,它不会跑,
Terrible things will happen, so
可怕的事情会发生,所以
you definitely wanna do this,
你一定要这样做,
I don't believe you need to do this if you're not in
我不相信你不需要这样做,如果你在
a workspace,
一个工作区,
I think if you just have an app by itself,
我想,如果你只有一个应用程序本身
you can leave that unset, and it'll work fine,
你可以把设置,它会工作很好,
So that, we did that for tweet right here, so
因此,我们在这里做了推特,所以
let's do it now for Twitter user,
让我们为Twitter用户,现在就做
Twitter user is default in class definition,
Twitter用户默认的类定义,
I want that to be extension also, and of course,
我也想要,扩展,当然,
I want current product module there,
我想当前的产品模块,
So that's all we need to do, and behind the scenes,
这就是我们要做的,在幕后,
Xcode has furiously written out this extension to make
Xcode疯狂地写了这个扩展
the vars work,
增值的工作,
But we have said that we're gonna write the class,
但我们已经说过,我们要编写的类,
So let's do that, let's create the class for
让我们这样做,让我们创建类
twitter user and for tweets,
twitter用户微博,
So we're gonna go to File > New > File,
所以我们要去File > New >文件,
it's just how we create any class, it's no different than
这只是我们如何创建任何类,它没有不同
any other class we've created, Cocoa Touch Class,
我们创建其他类,可可触摸类,
It's not a TableViewController,
这不是一个表,
it's an NSManagedObject, so we go down here, it's in somewhat
这是个NSManagedObject,我们去这里,它在某种程度上
alphabetical order, so, or is it here, NSManagedObject,
字母顺序排列的,所以,还是这里,NSManagedObject,
We know that Twitter user and tweet are representing
我们知道Twitter用户和微博是代表
the database as NSManagedObjects or
数据库作为nsmanagedobject或
subclasses thereof, which we're creating,
我们正在创建的子类,,
So we'll create the tweet one first and we hit Next,
我们将创建推一分之一和冲击下,
It says, where do you wanna put it, and
它说,你想把它放在哪里,
we'll put it in the same place as everything else,
我们会把它放在其他地方一样,
And here it is, we know that we're gonna have an error here
是这样的,我们知道,我们会有一个错误
immediately once this thing gets around to building that,
马上这个建筑,
and that's the NSManagedObject,
的NSManagedObject,
It's not gonna identify, it's not gonna know what that is
它不会识别,不会知道那是什么
until we say import CoreData,
直到我们说进口CoreData,
Don't forget this little piece in your subclass,
不要忘记这一小段子类,
But now we can put anything we want inside these curly
但是现在我们可以把任何我们想要在这些花
braces, and we're going to put a method in there,
牙套,我们将把一个方法,
So let's do the same thing here for Twitter user,
让我们为Twitter用户做同样的事,
Twitter user, in the same way,
Twitter用户,以同样的方式,
put everything in the same place,
把一切都在同一个地方,
Here it is, let's import CoreData,
在这里,我们进口CoreData,
Now when you're first creating your model file and
现在当你第一次创建文件和模型
you choose that extension thing, and
你选择扩展的事情,
hopefully you remember to do current project model, and
希望你记住当前项目模型,
all that stuff, the first time you build, and
所有的东西,你第一次构建
I'm gonna build here, you might get some errors,
我要建在这里,你可能会得到一些错误,
We didn't get any of the kind of errors that you get from
我们没有得到任何的错误,你得到的
things being out of whack, but if things are out of whack,
事情都是不正常的,但如果不正常,
one thing you can do is go up to the product menu,
你可以做的一件事就是去产品菜单,
and clean, just clean everything out,
和清洁,清洁,
That'll cause XCode to regenerate those extensions,
这将导致XCode再生这些扩展,
for example,
例如,
You can even hold down Option when you go to the Product
你甚至可以按住选择当你去产品
menu and then Clean Build Folder,
菜单,然后清洁建立文件夹,
And that will clean out all your drive data and
这将清除所有的数据和开车
rebuild absolutely everything,
重建一切,
So, those are options,
所以,这些都是选择,
And sometimes those are options just to do anytime
有时这些选项只是随时去做
something's kinda not really working right,
有点不正常工作,
Now we do have some errors, though, let's click and
现在我们有一些错误,让我们点击
see what this error is right here,
看看这个错误是在这里,
What is this saying?
这是什么意思吗?
It's saying cannot convert value tweet to specified
它说不能推到指定转换值
value tweet,
tweet价值,
Can anyone see what might be the problem with this line
谁能看到这条线可能是什么问题
of code right here?
的代码呢?
>> Exactly,
> >,
Yes, this is saying tweet, it doesn't know which one we
是的,这是说推特,它不知道我们哪一个
want, twitter,tweet or the smashtag,tweet,
想要的,推特,推特或smashtag,推特,
So we have to, in Swift, fully specify which one we want,
所以我们必须迅速,完全指定哪一个我们想要的,
So this one is the twitter,tweet from our
这一个是推特,推特从我们
old code,
旧代码,
And once we fix that,
一旦我们解决这个问题,
then now it knows what we're talking about and all is well,
然后现在知道我们讨论的是一切都很好,
All right, so
好吧,那么
now we've really got our core data stuff all ready to go,
现在我们真的有我们的核心数据的东西都准备好了,
We've got the classes, we've got our data model explained,
我们的类,我们有我们的数据模型解释说,
all that stuff,
所有的东西,
What we're gonna do next is have our main MVC right here,
接下来我们要做的是让我们的主要MVC,
Every time it fetches tweets,
每次获取tweet,
we're gonna have it put that tweet in the database,
我们会把它推在数据库中,
Once it loads up the database, then we can build this other
一旦加载数据库,然后我们可以建立其他
MVC that will query the database,
MVC将查询数据库,
So this is gonna be kind of the loading one,
所以这是装运,
That's gonna be the querying one,
要查询的,
Now, I might be quite tempted to add this code to
现在,我可能会很想将这段代码添加到
TweetTableViewController,sw- ift,
TweetTableViewController sw -界面张力,
Remember the thing we spent the last lecture doing all
还记得我们上节课做度过的
this wonderful stuff?
这美好的东西呢?
This would be an obvious place, for example in search
这将是一个明显的地方,例如在搜索
for tweets where I'm getting the tweets back,
推,我推回来了,
this would be an obvious place to load up the database,
这将是一个明显的地方加载数据库,
However, I don't wanna do that here,
然而,在这里我不想这样做,
And why don't I wanna do that here?
在这里,我想为什么不这样做呢?
Because I have a perfectly good tweet
因为我有一个完美的tweet
table view controller here, an awesome MVC, very reusable,
表视图控制器,一个了不起的MVC,可重用,
You give it a search term, it'll load up with tweets,
你给它一个搜索词,它会加载微博,
I don't really wanna pollute it and
我不太想和污染它
make it non-reusable by tying it to my data model here,
使它不可重复使用的,把我的数据模型,
by making it a core data thing,
通过它的核心数据,
So how do I resolve that conundrum where I wanna keep
所以我怎么解决这个难题,我想保持
this thing reusable,
这个东西可重用,
but I still need to put this stuff in the database?
但是我还需要把这些东西放在数据库吗?
The answer is, I'm gonna subclass this controller,
答案是,我要子类这个控制器,
I'm gonna make another MVC that is going to inherit
我要让另一个MVC继承
all the capabilities of this nice generic one, and
这个通用的所有功能,
add the core data stuff,
添加的核心数据,
So I'm just gonna go File > New File,
所以我要去文件>新建文件,
Cocoa Touch class, I'm gonna make it not a subclass of any
可可触摸类,我要让它没有的一个子类
iOS class, but a subclass of TweetTableViewController,
iOS类,但是TweetTableViewController的子类,
This is my nice generic reusable one,
这是我漂亮的通用的可重用的一个,
I'm gonna make this a subclass of that,
我要让这个的一个子类,
I'm gonna call it SmashTweetTableViewController,
我要叫它SmashTweetTableViewController,
Cuz it uses my smash data model,
因为它使用我粉碎数据模型,
So I'm just gonna create that, here we go,
所以我要创建,我们开始吧,
put it in the same place as always other things,
把它放在同一个地方一如既往,
I mean we're gonna just delete all these code out here,
我的意思是我们会删除所有这些代码,
Here it is,
在这里,
I always do that just to make it clearer to you what I'm
我总是这样做只是为了让你我更清晰
actually adding in this things,
加入这个东西,
So I have this SmashTweetTableViewController
所以我有这个SmashTweetTableViewController
and I can go to my story board for example and
我可以去我的故事板和例子
select this controller,
选择这个控制器,
And go to Identity,
去身份,
and instead of making it a TweetTableViewController,
而不是让它TweetTableViewController,
I'm gonna make it a SmashTweetTableViewController,
我要让它SmashTweetTableViewController,
So now, this is going to do all the things that
现在,这是要做的所有的事情
TweetTableViewController does,
TweetTableViewController,
plus anything I put in this sub class,
加上我放在这个接头类,
Now, unfortunately, we didn't
现在,不幸的是,我们没有
get all the way to designing our generic reusable one,
得到所有我们通用的可重用设计,
so that it was really nice and subclassable,
所以这是很好的和subclassable,
Specifically, it will be really hard to subclass search
具体地说,它将很难子类搜索
for tweets and then get inside here, in this closure and
tweet,然后进入这里,关闭和
do something when these tweets happen,
做一些当这些tweet发生,
So I'm gonna make my generic TweetTableViewController
所以我要让我的通用TweetTableViewController
a little more subclassable,
更subclassable
What I'm gonna do is take this code right here and
我要做的就是把这个代码
make a little method out of it,
做一个小方法,
insert tweets I'm gonna call it,
插入微博我要叫它,
Okay, I'm just gonna create a new method called insertTweets
好的,我要创建一个名为insertTweets的新方法
that's gonna do what that code I just cut out there is,
这是要做什么,代码我就删掉,
we'll put it up here,
我们会把它放在这里,
Func insertsTweets, it can take some new tweets
Func insertsTweets,它可以采取一些新的tweet
which is gonna be in array of Twitter,tweet,
会在数组的推特,推特,
It's gonna have that same code in there, obviously I don't
它会有相同的代码,很显然我不喜欢
need this weak self business here, because I'm not inside
需要这个弱自我业务在这里,因为我不是在里面
the closure here, and it's going to do it,
关闭,它会这样做,
I'm gonna leave this essentially internal,
我要离开这个内部,
remember that in default internal,
记住,在默认的内部,
which means it can be overwritten or called,
这意味着它可以被覆盖或叫,
If I made that private,
如果我做了,私人,
subclasses would not be able to overwrite it,
子类不能覆盖它,
Unfortunately there's nothing like protected in Swift where
不幸的是,没有什么比保护在斯威夫特
it's like subclassers can override it but people can't
就像子类可以重写,但人不能
call it, unfortunately there's no such thing as that,
称呼它,不幸的是,没有这种东西,
All right, so we have to leave this internal and but now
好了,所以我们不得不离开这个内部和现在
I can take this method in my subclass here and override it,
我可以把这个方法子类重写它,
So I just put it here and say override, so
所以我就把它放在这里说覆盖,所以
Swift knows that I'm overriding this thing,
迅速知道我重写这个东西,
Then I'm gonna let Super do its work,
然后我要让超级做其工作,
And then I'm going to call a method on myself,
然后我要对自己调用一个方法,
updateDatabase(with newTweets), all right?
updateDatabase(newTweets)?
And that's going to update my database, so I'm gonna have
要更新我的数据库,所以我要拥有的
a private func here called updateDatabase (with tweets),
一个私人func叫updateDatabase(微博),
it's gonna be a Twitter,tweet,
它会是一个推特,推特,
Sorry, I keep hitting this tiny button right there,
对不起,我一直打这个小按钮,
That's just going to put these tweets into Core Data,
就是要把这些tweet核心数据,
And of course it's complaining because import Twitter and
当然这是抱怨,因为Twitter和进口
I'm starting using Twitter now,
我现在开始使用Twitter,
I might as well put it now import CoreData because this
我现在不妨把它导入CoreData因为这
By the way,
顺便说一下,
SmashTweetTableViewController is obviously is
SmashTweetTableViewController显然是
going to be doing a lot of core data stuff as well,
要做很多核心数据的东西,
Everyone see what I did there?
每个人都明白我在做什么?
I just subclass this and I'm putting all my smash tag,
我只是这个子类,我把我所有的粉碎标签,
smash core data stuff into this subclass, so
粉碎核心数据到这个子类
that the super class remains completely generic,
超类是完全通用的,
I just had to make my super class a little
我不得不让我的超类
more subclassible,
更subclassible,
Now, as with any MVC,
现在,对于任何MVC,
we want to think about the model of this SmashTable,
我们要思考这个SmashTable的模型,
SmashTweetTableViewController, of course it's going to
SmashTweetTableViewController,当然会
inherit the model of its super class,
继承超类的模型,
But I'm also gonna add a model here,
但我也会添加一个模型,
which is the database to use,
数据库的使用,
And I'm gonna do it by passing in a PersistentContainer,
我要做PersistentContainer通过,
Now normally we probably want this to be the app delegate
现在通常我们可能想要这个应用程序委托
view, the app delegate persistence container,
看来,应用委托持久性容器,
But I wanna allow people who are using my MVC,
但是我想允许人们使用MVC,
to use any database they want,
他们想要使用任何数据库,
I don't wanna force them to use that app delegate one,
我不想强迫他们使用这个应用程序委托,
Having said that, I am gonna have the default value of
已经说过,我要的默认值
this, go ahead and be that,
继续,,,
So I'm gonna say (UIApplication,shared,delegate
所以我想说(UIApplication、分享委托
as?, AppDelegate)?,persistentConta-
的吗?
iner,
内心的,
That's just the default value but
这是默认值
this is a non-private var, so
这是一个私人var
I'm using this ViewController could set the container and
我用这个ViewController可以设置容器和
cause it to show things in a certain database,
因为它显示事情在某些数据库,
That is essentially my model, my model is this database,
这本质上是我的模型,这是我的模型数据库,
All this class does though is write to the database,
所有这门课虽然是写数据库,
it's just updating the database,
只是更新数据库,
All its UI it inherits from the super class which is non
所有的UI非从超类继承
database oriented,
面向数据库的,
So how do we update this database?
那么,我们如何更新该数据库?
What do we need to do?
我们需要做什么?
Well, one thing is, I don't really wanna update this thing
嗯,有一件事是,我不太想更新这个东西
on the main queue, because,
在主队列,因为,
I don't know if my super class might fetch a thousand tweets,
我不知道如果我的超类可能会卖一千条,
And do I really wanna be blocking the main queue while
,我真的想要阻止主队列
I go write a thousand tweets into my database?
我写了一千条微博进入数据库?
No way, so I'm gonna take my container right here, and
没有办法,所以我要把我的容器,和
I'm going to ask it to perform something on a background
我要问它执行一些背景
thread,
线程,
A background queue, and you can see, here's the argument,
背景队列,你可以看到,这里的论点,
it's a closure and it takes one argument,
一个闭包,它接受一个参数,即
I double-clicked on it there,
我双击后,
I'm gonna use trailing closure syntax even,
我要使用后关闭的语法,
So this one argument right here,
所以这里的一个参数,
This is the manage object context for that other queue,
这是其他队列的管理对象上下文,
the one that I'm allowed to use inside here,
我允许使用里面的,
In order to update my database,
为了更新我的数据库,
So I'm just gonna use that context and put these tweets,
所以我要用这个上下文和把这些推文,
these new tweets that I got right here,
这些新的推文,我在这里,
I'm gonna put them in the database one by one,
我要把它们放在数据库一个接一个地
I'm just gonna say for
我只是想说
twitterInfo in this tweets and then add tweet,
twitterInfo在这个tweet,然后加入推特,
So, how do I do this piece of it,
所以,我怎么做这一块,
How do I add a tweet?
我如何添加一个推特?
And by tweet there, I mean the tweet in our data model,
的推特,推特,我的意思是我们的数据模型,
That's what I wanna do,
这就是我想做的,
Add a tweet in our data model that matches this Twitter info
添加一个tweet匹配这个Twitter信息在我们的数据模型
that I got,
我得到了,
All right, so we're gonna put the method in tweet in
好吧,所以我们要把推特的方法
our subclass of tweet that we created right here,
我们的推特的子类创建,
that's currently empty,
这是目前空,
We're gonna put a static method in there to either go
我们要去把一个静态方法
out and find a tweet that matches that twitter info or
并找到一个匹配,twitter的微博信息
to create one if there's not one there,
创建一个如果没有一个,
So that way they'll keep being unique, because if we get
所以这样他们会保持独特,因为如果我们得到的
the same tweet we'll find it and just return the one that's
相同的微博我们会发现它的返回
already there versus creating a new one,
已有与创建一个新的,
So I'm gonna call this thing,
所以我要叫这个东西,
it's gonna be static or if its a class,
它会是静态的或者它的一个类,
we can say class func findOrCreatTweet, matching,
我们可以说类func findOrCreatTweet匹配,
twitterInfo and that's going to be a Twitter,tweet,
twitterInfo是推特,推特,
That's the info that's gonna be passed into it,
这是会传递给它的信息,
And I need to know what context to go look in, so
我需要知道上下文去看看,
I'm gonna say, in context, NSMan, I need some more space,
我想说,在上下文中,NSMan,我需要更多的空间,
MSManagedObjectContext, right there,
MSManagedObjectContext,,
And it's just going to return a tweet,
要返回一个微博,
So this static method, class method is just going to go and
所以这个静态方法,类方法就是去
look in the database and find this thing and
请在数据库中找到这个东西
if it can find it, then it'll just create a new one,
如果能找到它,那么它会创建一个新的,
So, we have to import Twitter, (let's get rid of this), and
所以,我们不得不进口Twitter,(让我们摆脱这个),
so how are we going to do this?
所以我们要怎么做呢?
Well this method,
这个方法,
pretty straight forward based on all you know in Core Data,
很直接的核心数据,基于你所知道的
First, I'm going to create a fetch request to go find
首先,我要创建一个获取请求去寻找
this tweet,
这个微博,
Le's do that tha's easy how about let request equal and
乐的,那如何让要求平等,很简单
remember I have to statically type this actually so
记得我必须静态类型确实如此
this is going to be an NS,
这将是一个NS,
Fetch request,
获取请求,
The fetch is what?
fetch是什么?
Tweets,
微博,
So I'm gonna use this nice Tweet,fetchRequest
所以我要用这个漂亮的Tweet,fetchRequest
method to get one,
方法一,
So that got me a fetch request,
所以让我获取请求,
A fetch request that's on tweets,
获取请求的微博,
That's what I have there and
这就是我在那里
then I have to have a predicate for this,
然后我必须有一个谓语,
So I'm gonna say the request predicate this is the thing
所以我想说请求谓词的事情
that gonna say which tweets do you want in the database?
会说你要哪tweet的数据库?
So predicate here, and which tweets do we want?
这里谓词,我们想要推?
Well, we want a tweet where the unique key,
我们想要一个唯一键推,
remember the unique key is in our data model,
记得独特的关键是在我们的数据模型中,
I'll be going back to this data model often,
我将回到这个数据模型通常,
But see here's that unique key right there,
但是看到这唯一键,
We wanna know when that unique key matches what
我们想知道什么时候那独特的关键比赛
the person passed in here,
通过在这里的人,
The twitter info of what they passed in,
twitter信息的传入,
So that's %@", and that's twitterInfo,identifier,
% @”,twitterInfo,标识符,
So it turns out identifier
结果标识符
that in our twitter info dot tweet,
,在我们点推特,推特信息
That's the thing that you need for all time for a tweet,
这是你需要的东西时间一条微博,
It's always the same for
它总是一样的
the tweet even if you download it multiple times,
的推特即使你多次下载它,
it's always the same,
它总是相同的,
Now what about our sort predicate here, or
现在我们的谓词,或
our sort descriptors rather?
我们的描述符,而?
We actually don't need any sort descriptors
我们不需要任何类型描述符
because this better match exactly one or zero,
因为这更好的完全匹配一个或零,
So you don't need to put zero things or one thing in order,
所以你不需要把零或一件事,
So you don't need a sort descriptor and
所以你不需要一个描述符和排序
if you don't specify a sort descriptor you'll get them
如果你不指定一个类描述符你会得到它们
back in random order,
在随机顺序,
But again, we don't care what that is because it
但是,我们不在乎,是因为它
better be zero or one or we've got problems,
更好的是零或一个或我们有问题,
So how do I fetch this thing?
所以我拿这个东西怎么样?
Very easy, I'm just gonna say let the matches in
很简单,我只是想说让比赛
the database equal context,fetch(request),
数据库等背景下,获取(请求),
Now the only thing about this is it throws,
现在唯一是它抛出,
Cuz it might not be able to access the database,
因为它可能无法访问数据库,
It could be all kinds of problems, whatever,
它可以是各种各样的问题,无论如何,
So I'm gonna put this in a do try, a do catch here,
所以我要把这个在做尝试,做抓,
So we'll do do and put try here,
所以我们会做的,在这里,
And we'll put catch, (I'll talk about what we're gonna do
我们会把抓,(我将谈谈我们要做的
when we catch an error there),
当我们发现一个错误),
All right, so we got the matches,
好吧,我们有比赛,
So these matches what's the type of this match,
这些比赛是什么类型的这场比赛,
We got an error here, some error,
我们这里有一个错误,有些错误,
Context,
背景下,
Sorry,
对不起,
NSManageObjectContext,
So what is the type of this matches right here?
所以这个匹配的类型是什么?
Anyone wanna guess?
谁想猜一猜吗?
Let's look, it's array of tweets,
让我们看,它是一系列微博,
Of course I dispatched,
我当然派遣,
I get it back an array of Tweet,
我把它弄回来一个Tweet数组,
Excellent,
杰出、
And it should be that the matches count
它应该是匹配数
if it's greater that zero, then I found my tweet,
如果是更大的,零,然后我发现我的微博,
In fact I can just return it,
事实上,我可以返回它,
Return matches(0),
返回匹配(0),
So I found that unique tweet,
所以我发现独特的微博,
I'm actually gonna put an assert here though
我要把一个断言
that if the matches,count is greater than one,
,如果匹配,数大于1,
then some kind of database inconsistency,
然后某种数据库不一致,
because somehow in that unique field
因为在这种独特的领域
there's more than one of them in there so that will be bad,
有不止一个人这样会坏,
Maybe I'll put the name of the method in here tweet dot
也许我会把方法的名称在这里推点
that database inconsistency or something like that so,
数据库不一致或类似的东西,所以,
I'm putting a little assert,
我把一个断言,
Now that should never happen if I've written my code
现在,如果我写我的代码不应该发生
properly, it should never be possible for
正确,应该不可能
two tweets to get in there,
两个微博,
There would have to be a bug somewhere else in my code,
其他地方会有一个错误在我的代码中,
that's why I'm asserting here,
这就是为什么我在这里断言,
cuz I want it to crash if that happens so that I notice it,
因为我想让它崩溃如果发生这种情况,我注意到它,
Things aren't being duplicated without my knowledge,
事情并不在我不知情的情况下被复制,
Now what about this catch right here?
现在这里赶呢?
What if we tried to do this fetch to get those tweets and
如果我们试图去取回这些tweet和
it fails?
失败了吗?
Some problem with the database or something,
一些问题与数据库什么的,
What should we do in here?
在这里我们应该做什么?
Well, we could fatal error and crash,
我们可以致命错误和崩溃,
That's what save context does,
什么拯救环境,
by the way, in the App Delegate, it just crash,
顺便说一下,在应用程序委托,它只是崩溃,
We could look at the error and try to figure out what it is,
我们可以看看错误并试图找出它是什么,
things like that,
类似这样的事情,
But you know, I don't actually know what the person who's
但你知道,我其实不知道的人
calling this find your create tweet wants me to do
调用这个找到你创建微博要我做
if there's a database error,
如果有一个数据库错误,
I'm not sure, do they want me to ignore it?
我不确定,他们想让我忽略它吗?
Do they want me to crash?
他们想让我崩溃吗?
Do they want me to try again or something?
他们想让我再试一次吗?
What do they want?
他们想要什么?
So when you don't really know what your caller wants to do,
所以,当你不知道对方想要做什么,
why not just rethrow the error,
为什么不重新抛出的错误,
When you rethrow, that means this method throws,
当你重新抛出,这意味着该方法抛出,
Everyone understand what I did there?
每个人都明白我在做什么吗?
I mean this method findOrCreateTweet throw,
我的意思是这个方法findOrCreateTweet扔,
And the only where it throws is a rethrows if this
唯一的,它将是一个重新抛出如果这
generates an error,
生成一个错误,
So when we call this findOrCreateTweet back in our
所以当我们称之为findOrCreateTweet回到我们
other class where we have to be careful cuz it throws now,
其他类,我们必须要小心因为现在抛出,
So I like to use try,
所以我喜欢用试试,
But if we get down here,
但是如果我们得到下面,
then we made it passed here without finding a match, so
然后我们通过这里没有找到一个匹配,
here's what we need to create the tweet,
这就是我们需要创建微博,
So I'm gonna say let tweet equal, and
所以我想说让tweet平等,
how do we create a tweet?
我们如何创建一个推特?
We just say TweetContext context,
我们只是说TweetContext上下文,
So that creates a tweet in the database,
数据库中创建了一个微博,
Now I can just set the tweet fields by setting the vars,
现在我可以设置微博领域中通过设置var,
like the tweets, that's actually do that unique first,
像微博一样,其实这样做独特的第一,
that's important one,
这很重要,
So that's TwitterInfo,identifier,
这是TwitterInfo,标识符,
We're gonna make sure we said that, if we don't said that,
我们要确保我们说,如果我们不能说,
then we might start getting problems here because every
然后我们可以开始因为每一个问题
body is unique is gonna be the same zero or blank,
身体是独一无二的是相同的零个或空白,
either or something,
之类的,
How about the tweets text?
微博的文本呢?
Let's set that to the twitterInfo,text,
让我们集合twitterInfo、文本
Here's created tweet,created,
这是推创建,创建,
That's twitterInfo,created and
twitterInfo,创建和
then we'll return the tweet,
然后我们返回tweet,
Now, this line over here is gonna give us an error,
现在,这条线是要给我们一个错误,
as soon as it catches up,
就追上了,
And this error's kinda weird one,
这个错误有点奇怪,
It says cannot assign a value of type 'Date' to
它说不能赋值类型的“约会”
type 'NSDate?',
类型“NSDate ?”
And I mentioned on one of the slides from last time,
我从上次提到的幻灯片,
that in the database, dates are NS dates,
在数据库中,日期NS日期,
But I also mentioned that you can automatically bridge
但我也提到过,您可以自动桥
a date to an NS date,
一个NS日期的日期,
And you can do that with as,
你可以这样做的,
So I can say as NSDate,
所以我可以说NSDate,
And that will always work,
总是工作,
This as will always work as long as this Is an NSDate,
这是永远的工作只要这是nsdata,
then this as will always work, it always can bridge across,
那么这个总是工作,它总是可以桥接,
So this is kind of unfortunate that you have to do this for
这是一种不幸,你必须这样做
your dates, but you do, sorry,
你的约会,但你,对不起,
Okay, there's one more thing in tweet, though,
好了,有一件事在推特,不过,
What's the missing thing in tweet?
失踪的事在微博是什么?
Tweet,tweeter,
推特,推特,
I've got to set my tweeter here,
我要把我推特,
I just created this tweet, I gotta set who the tweeter is,
我刚刚创建的这个微博,我要推特是谁,
So to do the tweeter, I'm gonna go do this exact
所以推特,我要去做这个
same method over in TwitterUser,
同样的方法在TwitterUser,
So that I can create a Twitter user the exact same way,
这样我可以创建一个Twitter用户相同的方式,
So we'll call it find or create Twitter user,
所以我们叫它找到或创建Twitter用户,
I, kind of pre canned right here cuz you're not gonna
我,以前这里因为你不会罐头
learn anything from me typing this,
学习任何东西,从我打字,
basically this exact same thing in again,
基本上,这同一件事情,
Gotta import twitter,
要进口推特上
But it's exactly the same, it has the same exact logic,
但这是完全相同的,它有相同的逻辑,
I'm doing exactly the same thing,
我在做同样的事情,
I'm even rethrowing,
我甚至将,
just creating the twitter user if I can't find it,
只是创建一个twitter用户如果我找不到它,
And for a twitter user, it's handle, the person's handle,
对于twitter用户,处理,人的处理,
@ whatever, is the unique identifier,
@,是唯一标识符,
So now that we know how to create a Twitter user
现在我们知道如何创建一个Twitter用户
using that I can say Tweeter equals Twitter user,
我能说推特= Twitter用户使用,
Find or there it is, finally recognize it,
发现或,终于承认,
Okay, find or create Twitter user, and
好的,找到或创建Twitter用户,
we wanna use the Tweets user field, Twitter,
我们想要使用推特用户领域,推特,
Lowercase Twitter info dot user, that's the user,
小写的Twitter信息。用户,用户,
Then we'll do it in the same context of course,
然后我们将用同样的背景当然,
Now this throws, so we have to try this,
现在这把,所以我们要试试这个,
And if it can't do it, I'm just going to fail again,
如果它不能这样做,我将再次失败,
Here maybe I want to maybe re-throw again, possibly,
这里我想也许再次抛出收到,可能
I might even wanna crash or something, I don't know,
我甚至想崩溃或什么东西,我不知道,
It's not clear to me,
我不清楚,
what to do if I can't create the twitter,
要做什么如果我不能创建twitter,
If Tweeter is something that has to be set for
如果推特是必须设置的
a tweet to make any sense in the database, then I probably
数据库中的任何意义的tweet,然后我可能
do wanna re-throw or do something terrible here,
想抛出收到,做一些可怕的事情
But by just saying try, instead I'm just giving up,
而是说试一试,我就放弃,
okay I'm just not setting the tweeter,
好吧我只是不设置来说,
So, there could be tweets that
所以,可能会有微博
are created with no tweeter there,
创建与没有推特,
Twitter user, yeah,
Twitter用户,是的,
twitter user doesn't need to be an optional there,
twitter用户不需要一个可选的,
Sorry, I made that accidentally,
对不起,我不小心,
So It's just going to return a twitter user,
所以它只是返回一个twitter用户,
And the try makes it into an optional twitter user which is
试着让它变成一个可选的twitter用户
okay because tweeter,
因为推特,
this relationship, is an optional twitter user,
这种关系,是一个可选的twitter用户,
It comes out of our data model,
它来自我们的数据模型,
So, that's it, that's how we create a tweet,
所以,就是这样,这就是我们创建一个微博,
We need to use this method right here to put
我们需要使用这个方法
those tweets in the database,
在数据库中,
So, let's go back to here,
因此,让我们回到这里,
Let's go to our SmashTweetTableViewController,
让我们去SmashTweetTableViewController,
And here, where we wanna add the tweets, we'll just say
在这里,我们想加入微博,我们就说
Let a Tweet equal Tweet,findOrCreateTweet,
让翠特平等,findOrCreateTweet留言;
We'll pass it, the Twitter info,
我们会通过Twitter信息,
That's this Twitter info right here that was passed to us and
这是这里的Twitter信息,传递给我们
these Tweets,
这些微博,
And in context, we're gonna use our containers context,
在上下文中,我们要使用我们的容器上下文,
Sorry, we're not using our container context,
对不起,我们不使用容器上下文,
We're using this context right here,
我们使用这个背景,
So we use this little context right here,
所以我们用这个小环境,
Now of course we know this thing throws right here,
当然我们知道这事扔在这里,
So we'll just do try question mark here,
所以我们在这里尝试问号,
Because here I do know that when I'm updating
因为我知道当我更新
if I can't create that tweet, I'm just gonna drop it,
如果我不能创建这个微博,我要放弃,
the database,
数据库,
It's not gonna hurt anything if just not collecting
它不会伤害任何东西如果不收集
the data it needs too,
它需要的数据,
There's really nothing I can do about it whatever
其实我能为力
the database error is it's in there maybe I could report
数据库错误是在那里也许我可以报告
an error to the user and say couldn't update data base but
一个错误给用户说但不能更新数据基地
a lot of times user are like what the heck is that,
很多时候用户就像究竟是怎么一回事,
So here dropping it is probably fine,
这里下降可能是好,
Now notice we have a warning here, see this warning?
注意这里有一个警告,看到这个警告?
It says let tweet equals and you never use tweet, and
让微博=和你永远不使用推特,和
in fact I don't wanna use tweet,
事实上我不想使用微博,
So what do you do in this case where I found and
所以你做什么工作在这种情况下,我发现
create this tweet but I actually don't want it,
创建这个tweet但我真的不想要它,
I don't wanna do anything,
我不想做任何事情,
I just wanted it to get created if it wasn't there,
我只是想让它得到了如果它不在那里,
Well here you can say, "Under bar",
这里你可以说,“在酒吧”,
If you say _ =" something it means I'm ignoring the return
如果你说_ = "这意味着我忽略了返回的东西
value, which is fine,
值,这是可以的,
I don't need the return value I just want this thing created
我不需要返回值我想这事了
in the database, doesn't have to do anything,
在数据库中,不需要做任何事情,
Everybody following me so far here?
每个人都跟着我到目前为止吗?
So now we have loaded up the database,
现在我们有装数据库,
That's it, That's all of the code we need
就是这样,这就是我们需要的所有代码
to load our database up with all these tweets,
加载数据库所有这些推文,
Now let's go ahead and print some database statistics here
现在让我们去打印一些数据库统计数据
just to see if this is working before we go off and
只是为了看看这是工作在我们离开之前,
do our UI for a new MBC,
做我们的UI MBC,
So I'm gonna say, printDatabaseStatistics and
所以我会说,printDatabaseStatistics和
I'm gonna create a new private func here called
我要创建一个新的私人func叫
printDatabaseStatistics,
Copy, paste,
复制,粘贴,
And what I want this thing to do is tell me how many tweets
我想要这个东西做告诉我多少tweet
and how many twitter users are in the database,
和有多少twitter用户在数据库中,
That's all I wanted to do here,
这就是我想做的,
So if I wanna do anything in the database, if
如果我想做任何事在数据库中,如果
I wanna look in the database I obviously need a context,
我想看数据库中我显然需要一个背景下,
I have to have a context to
我必须有一个上下文
look inside the database or whatever,
看在数据库或其他,
So what context am I gonna use?
上下文我要使用什么?
I'm gonna say, if I can let my let context equal my
我想说,如果我可以让我让上下文相同
containers?,viewContext,
viewContext,容器?
Now the viewContext Is the mainqueue context for
现在viewContext mainqueue上下文
this database,
这个数据库,
So, I'm gonna have printDatabaseStatistics,
所以,我要有printDatabaseStatistics,
It's not inside this closure, so
这不是在这个闭包,
it's not gonna use this context,
它不会使用这样的背景下,
We'll have it use the main viewContext,
我们会使用主要viewContext,
This is pretty much, unless you had it perform background
这是相当多的,除非你把它做背景
tasks, this is pretty much the only context you have, so
任务,这几乎是唯一的上下文,所以
we'll have it do on the main context,
我们要做的主要背景,
So how am I gonna find out how many tweets there are?
那么我要如何找到有多少条?
Okay, I'm gonna create a request and do a fetch,
好的,我要创建一个请求并取回,
So NSFetchRequest,
所以NSFetchRequest,
And this one is a request for tweets,
这个是一个tweet请求
Equals Tweet,fetchRequest,
= Tweet,fetchRequest,
So now I got this request, the fetch request
现在我有这个请求,获取请求
I need no predicate here because I want all the tweets,
我需要没有谓词,因为我希望所有的微博,
If you have no predicate that means give me them all,
如果你没有谓语就意味着给我,
So that's what I want, and so now I'm just going to
这就是我想要的,所以现在我要
say here if I can let the tweetCount equal
说如果我能让tweetCount相等
trying to access the context to fetch this request,
试图访问上下文获取这个请求,
Which it may or not be able to do,
它是否可以做,
But if it can then you understand what I did there?
但是如果你能理解我所做的吗?
Then I'm going to get the count,
然后我将得到计数,
What's the type of that expression?
这个表达式的类型是什么?
Optional array of tweets,
可选的微博,
Because this returns an array of tweets if it
因为这个tweet如果它返回一个数组
doesn't throw and this turns into an optional,
不把这变成一个可选的,
So this is an optional array of tweets,
这是一个可选的微博,
Here I'm optional chaining,
这里我可选的链接,
So if that's not new then I get to continue and
如果这不是新的然后我得到继续
get the count,
数,
This is just array's count, this is a method count in
这仅仅是数组的计算,这是一个计数的方法
array a var for the count in array,
在数组,数组的var计算
Now I've got the tweetCount, now I'm just gonna say print,
现在我有tweetCount,现在我只是想说打印,
tweetCount, tweets, and that's it,
tweetCount、微博,就是这样,
I fetch them all,
我取回,
I just fetched every tweet in the entire database,
我只是获取每条tweet在整个数据库,
just to find out how many there were,
为了找出有多少,
What if there's a 100,000 Tweets in there?
如果有100000微博呢?
I'm really gonna fetch and that, of course we know that
我真的要卖,当然我们知道
it's only gonna fault sum of min until I ask for the data,
它只会错之和最小,直到我问的数据,
So it's not that bad but
所以它没那么糟糕,但
there's a better way to do this,
有一个更好的方法来做到这一点,
By the way here's another, before I show that,
顺便说一下这是另一个,在我表明,
See this request I made this separate variable, right here,
看到这个请求我做这个独立的变量,在这里,
That's not actually necessary,
实际上这并不是必要的,
I can just take this request right here and
我可以把这个请求
put it right in,
正确的,
To here,
到这里,
Watch this,
看这个,
Cut, paste, and get rid of that,
剪切、粘贴和摆脱,
That's because the fetch method takes
这是因为fetch方法
any kind of fetch request,
任何一种获取请求,
It takes anything whose type is a fetchRequest result
需要任何的类型是fetchRequest结果
basically, which is a protocol,
基本上,这是一个协议,
And so I didn't have to create that other variable,
所以我不需要创建其他变量,
And notice I don't have to statically type this because
注意这个,因为我不需要静态类型
this would take anything that returns a fetchRequest,
这将返回一个fetchRequest,
It'd return something,
它会返回一些东西,
So anyway, so
所以无论如何,
what's the better way to do counting right here?
有什么更好的方法来计算在这里吗?
Is I'm gonna say if let tweeterCount, so
我想说如果让tweeterCount,所以呢
I'll count the tweeters in this better way, equals try
我会计算高音在这个更好的方法,等于试一试
to get the context,count for:
上下文,计数:
TwitterUsers,fetchRequest, okay, all twitter users,
TwitterUsers fetchRequest,好吧,所有的twitter用户,
Then I can print the twitterCount,
然后我可以打印twitterCount,
Twitter users,
Twitter用户,
So this method count is very much like fetch but
这方法很像卖但计数
it doesn't is still kinda evaluating this fetch request,
它不仍有点评估这个获取请求,
it's getting the same things,
同样的事情,
In this case we're counting users, but
在这种情况下,我们计算的用户,但是
it's really just asking the data base,
它只是要求数据基础,
If I were to fetch this, how many would you give me?
如果我拿这个,你会给我多少?
So it's all done on the database side,
这是所有在数据库端完成,
nothing actually has to get fetched,
没有什么实际上获取,
So it's just another method count,
这只是另一种方法计算,
But it does throw, as well, in the same was as Fetch does,
但它扔,相同的是获取,
So we still have to do try,
所以我们仍然要做尝试,
So this whole expression right here, isn't option int,
所以整个表达式,不是选择int,
So I'm unwrapping it with if let, and printing it out,
如果让我打开它,打印出来,
Got all that?
得到了所有吗?
Let's cross our fingers here that this
这让我们交叉手指
all works that we've got all this database learning,
所有作品,我们有这个数据库学习,
And we gonna print our database
我们会打印数据库
statistics and it all gonna work,
统计所有要工作,
Here we go and this is just some junk from IOS there so
好了,这只是一些垃圾从IOS
we'll ignore that,
我们会忽略,
Right here let's search for some,
让我们找一些,
Let's search for, how about hash tag stan,
让我们寻找,散列标签斯坦,
well let's do hash tag stan, yeah, that's a good one,
好让我们做散列标签斯坦,是的,这是一个很好的一个,
All right, it wants to use my Twitter account,
好吧,它希望用我的Twitter帐户,
Sure, here it is, and,
当然,在这里,,
Uh-oh, look on the console there,
哦,看在控制台上,
Zero tweets, zero Twitter users,
零,零推特用户,
Maybe let's pull some more,
也许我们拉一些,
No, it's still zero tweets, zero Twitter user,
不,它仍然是零tweet,零Twitter用户,
Well it's not working,
这不是工作,
Anyone see anything in this code for
任何人看到这个代码的任何东西
why this is not working,?
为什么这是不工作,?
Yeah, we're doing a good job of loading up that database,
是的,我们正在做一份好工作的加载数据库,
but we never save it,
但是我们从来没有保存它,
So all that is just waste of time,
所以这只是浪费时间,
we need to say try, context, save,
我们需要说、上下文、保存
Now again I'm ignoring the error here,
现在我在这里忽略错误,
In a demo a lot of the time I use try, question mark because
在一个演示我尝试使用很多时候,问号,因为
I just don't have time to do the due catch and
我只是没有时间去捕捉和
handle all the errors,
处理所有的错误,
That's something you should
这是你应该的
be looking at the option of doing,
看着做的选择,
So here I'm just gonna save and
这里我要保存并
ignore any errors, alright?
忽略任何错误,对吧?
So that should fix it right?
所以,应该修理它?
Let's go see,
让我们去看看,
All right, here we go,
好吧,我们开始吧,
Hash tag Stanford,
散列标签斯坦福大学,
No,
不,
Zero tweet,
0条,
Zero Twitter users,
零Twitter用户,
I put that save in there,
我把它保存在那里,
What is going on?
什么是怎么回事?
I had to pull again,
我不得不再次拉,
Look, I pulled and it worked,
看,我把这工作,
What the heck is going on?
到底是怎么回事?
When I first loaded up it said zero tweets and
当我第一次装tweets和它说零
then now it's saying 57th,
然后现在是说第57位,
Something weird going on here,
奇怪的东西,
What's happening?
发生什么事情了?
Well, this is actually a multi threading problem,
这实际上是一个多线程问题,
Can anyone see the multi-threading problem here?
谁能看到这里的多线程问题吗?
No? I'm gonna put some print in,
没有?
so you can see it,
所以你可以看到它,
So watch this, print, starting database load,
所以看这个,打印,从数据库加载,
And then down here, when I'm done with the save here,
然后下面,当我完成了保存在这里,
I'm gonna just print, done loading database,
我要打印,完成加载数据库,
And there, so
在那里,所以
now let's run,
现在,让我们来运行,
All right, hash tag Stanford,
好了,散列标签斯坦福大学,
Got a crash there, database inconsistency, interesting,
有崩溃,数据库不一致,有趣,
So this is why we put this inserts in here,
所以这就是为什么我们把这个插入在这里,
Asserts in here, so let's see why do we think we have
断言在这里,让我们看看为什么我们认为我们有
a data basing consistency here?
数据基于一致性呢?
Yeah?
是吗?
>> That's what it is,
> >这是它是什么,
Yes, my search is backwards, there,
是的,我的搜索是向后的,,
I'm inserting here that matches,count == 1,
我在这里插入相匹配,计算= = 1,
So that's why that's crashing, okay,
这就是为什么崩溃,好吧,
Good, Let's
好,让我们
go back,
回去,
Now let's try again, hashtag Stanford,
现在,让我们再试一次,标签斯坦福大学,
Let's see what's going on down here,
下面让我们来看看发生了什么,
Starting database load, it prints the statistics, and
从数据库加载,它打印统计,
then it's done loading,
然后加载完成,
That's bad,
这是坏的,
You see, it's not waiting for
你看,这不是等待
it to be done loading before it prints the statistics,
它加载完成之前打印统计,
You see?
你看到了什么?
Now why is that happening?
现在为什么发生?
Because we're putting print databaseStatistics here after
因为我们将打印后databaseStatistics这里
downloading,
下载,
So why isn't it saying starting, done,
为什么不是说开始,完成,
and then printing?
然后打印?
Because this right here,
因为这里,
happens on a different queue,
发生在一个不同的队列,
So the way that this code goes is,
所以这段代码的方式,
starting, this execute returns immediately,
开始,这个执行立即返回,
Because all it does is put this
因为它所做的是把这个
closure onto the background task queue,
关闭后台任务队列,
Then this happens,
然后这一切发生的时候,
Then, this closure starts running on that background
然后,这个闭包开始运行在这一背景下
queue, loads up these things,
队列,加载了这些事情,
And it prints,
它打印,
Do you see what's going on there?
你看到那边发生了什么吗?
Everyone understand the multi-threading?
每个人都理解多线程?
So the way to make this work is to take print database
所以做这项工作的方法是采取打印数据库
statistics, and put it inside here,
统计数据,并把它在这里,
All right, cuz now it's not going to print the database
现在好了,因为它不会打印数据库
statistics until it's done,
统计数据,直到它完成
Now this has a problem though,
现在有一个难题,
Okay, this is very bad,
好的,这是非常糟糕的,
First of all, we're gonna have to do, I'm not sure why it's
首先,我们要做的,我不知道为什么
not complaining here, there we go, now it is,
不抱怨,好了,现在,
It wants to know, it wants self dot here, so
要知道,它希望self。,所以
I'm gonna do weak self to break that memory cycle,
我要做弱自我突破,记忆周期,
Hopefully everyone understands that now, what's going on,
希望每个人都明白,这是怎么回事,
Okay,
好吧,
But that's not the problem here,
但这不是问题,
There's an even worse problem,
有一个更糟糕的问题,
And in the interest of time,
由于时间关系,
I'm going to put a print down in here to show you something,
我要放下一个打印在这里给你看些东西,
If I'm gonna check to see if this code
如果我要看看这段代码
is running on the main thread,
运行在主线程,
So I'm gonna say IF,
所以我想说,如果
and the way you do that is you say thread,ismainthread,
你说你这样做的方法是线程,ismainthread,
Okay, if I'm in the main thread it'll be true,
好吧,如果我在主线程会是真的,
So I'm gonna say on main thread,
所以我想说在主线程,
And if it's not true, I'm gonna say off main thread,
如果这不是真的,我要从主线程说,
So let's see if this statistics is happening
让我们看看这个数据正在发生的事情
on the main thread or not,
在主线程,
I think many of you know which one it's going to be,
我想很多人都知道这将是哪一个,
By looking at the code here,
通过查看代码,
All right, here we go again, hash tag Stanford,
好吧,又来了,散列标签斯坦福大学,
Here we go,
我们开始吧,
Off main thread,
主线程,
Okay, why is it off the main thread?
好的,为什么从主线程?
Because I called print database statistics inside
因为我叫打印数据库统计进去
this closure, it happens on a background thread thus this
这个闭包,它发生在一个后台线程
entire method is happening off the main thread,
整个方法正在发生的主线程,
Now, is that a problem?
现在,这是一个问题吗?
That's a huge problem, because what context am I using here?
这是一个巨大的问题,因为我正在使用什么背景呢?
The mainQueue context,
mainQueue上下文,
ViewContext is the mainQueue context,
ViewContext mainQueue上下文,
I cannot be using the mainQueue context off the main
我不能使用mainQueue上下文主要
thread,
线程,
You see the problem here?
你看到这里的问题吗?
So it worked, but could have easily crashed or
它工作,但是可以轻松或坠毁
done something terrible,
做可怕的事情,
So how do we fix that?
那么,我们如何解决这个问题?
This is where we use that method I was telling
这就是我告诉我们使用方法
you about in context called perform,
你在上下文中执行,
I'm gonna say context perform this code on your safe queue,
点击安全队列上下文执行这段代码,
When I say context perform and I put this code in there,
当我说上下文执行和我把这段代码,
it says to that context, do this block but
它说,这种情况下,块,但这样做
whatever you do, do it on the right queue for you,
无论你做什么,对你做正确的队列,
And since this is the view context,
因为这是背景,
it's going to be back on the main thread,
这将是回到主线程,
watch,
手表,
Hashtag Stanford,
标签斯坦福大学,
Here we go back on main thread,
我们回到主线程,
So this perform right here is something that
所以这里的执行的东西
a lot of people would advise,
很多人建议,
always use it unless you're Inside one of these where it's
总是使用它,除非你在其中一个的
clearly using this context in this background thing,
显然使用这个背景在这个背景,
Any other time,
其他时间,
a lot of people say always wrap your calls in this,
很多人说总是在这个包裹你的电话,
That way, you'll never have a problem where some things
这样,你永远不会有一个问题,一些东西
being executed on the wrong thread, okay, wrong que,
被错误的线程上执行,好吧,错了,
Understood all that?
理解这一切吗?
A little crash course in core data thread safety there,
有点速成课核心数据线程安全,
All right, so this is great,
好的,这是伟大的,
We've got our database loading up, so
我们有我们的数据库加载,所以
we've got a database full of tweets,
我们有一个数据库的微博,
Now, we want to add some UI to show all this data somehow,
现在,我们要添加一些UI显示所有这些数据在某种程度上,
So let's go back to our storyboard and take a look,
让我们回到故事板,看一看,
what we got here,
我们所得到的,
And what kinda UI we're gonna have?
有点UI我们要什么?
Like I said, I'm just gonna have another MVC over here
就像我说的,我要有另一个MVC
that I'm gonna segue to, with a little bar button item,
我要继续,小工具栏按钮,
So how many of you figured out how to use a bar button item
所以你们中有多少人知道如何使用工具栏按钮
as part of your homework assignment I think?
你的作业我认为一部分?
But if you didn't you're gonna see today how to do it, and
但如果你今天没你会看到怎么做,和
it's quite simple,
这很简单,
So this new MVC that I'm gonna segue to, let's go ahead and
这新的MVC,我会继续,让我们继续
create an MVC for it, Cocoa Touch Class,
创建一个MVC,可可触摸类,
It is just going to be a sub class
它就是一个次级类
of UITableViewController,
UITableViewController,
I'm gonna call it SmashTweetersTableViewControl-
我要叫它SmashTweetersTableViewControl -
ler, so this is showing tweeters,
l,这是显示推特,
Remember this table's gonna show all the tweeters who
记住这个表会显示所有的高音
tweeted the tweets that are in the other MVC,
在其他MVC推的推,
We'll put it up at the, not in the Twitter project,
我们将把它的,而不是在Twitter的项目中,
that's for sure,
那是肯定的,
Let's put it down here, okay?
让我们把它在这里,好吗?
I always check this list, this one here or
我总是检查这个列表,这个
you end up with files all in random places,
你最终得到的文件都在随机的地方,
You don't want that,
你不想要,
Here it is, Again,
在这里,再一次,
I'm gonna delete all this stuff,
我要删除所有这些东西,
See it's a tableView, so
看到这是一个视图,所以
it's got all this UITableView, so we don't need any of this
它有所有这些UITableView,所以我们不需要这些
stuff as you're gonna see here,
你会看到,
This is our new TableViewController,
这是我们的新表,
Let's go ahead and
让我们继续
update our storyboard to segue to this thing,
更新我们的故事板segue这个东西,
So we'll go over here,
所以我们会在这里,
Let's create our bar button item to do the segue, so
让我们创建工具栏按钮segue,
I'm gonna search here for button,
我要在这里搜索按钮,
You never wanna put a button in here,
在这里,你永远不会想要把一个按钮
it'll look like it's gonna working, but it's not right,
它会看起来像它会工作,但它是不正确的,
Put a bar button in a bar,
在酒吧里放一个工具栏按钮,
So we'll call this Tweeter cuz that's what it shows, it shows
所以我们称之为推特因为这就是它所示,它显示了
the tweeters that tweeted all the tweets in this table,
推特,推特这个表的所有微博,
Let's get a TableViewController out,
,让我们一个表
here it is,
在这里,
TableViewController right there,
表,
Lets go ahead and segue from this,
让我们继续,继续,
Ctrl + drag,
Ctrl +拖,
Show segue, we're inside a navigation controller here,
显示segue,我们这里在导航控制器,
Let's set this segue identifier, we'll call this,
设这个segue标识符,我们叫这个,
what did I?
我什么?
I had a good name for this,
我有一个好名字,
Yes, Tweeters Mentioning Search Term,
是的,高音提到搜索词,
Cuz that's what this segue does,
因为这是这个segue做什么,
It show the tweeters that have mentioned this search
它显示了高音,提到这个搜索
term right here,
一项,
Let's also have our little cell here be a subtitle cell,
我们也有我们的小细胞是一个副标题细胞,
So we'll change that to subtitle,
所以我们会改变字幕,
And we need a reuse identifier for this cell right here,
我们需要一个重用标识符这个细胞,
We'll call this a TwitterUser Cell, cuz that's what it is,
我们称之为TwitterUser细胞,因为它是什么,
The Twitter user gonna be shown in this cell right here,
所示的Twitter用户将这个细胞,
All right, so that's it,
好吧,就是这样,
That's our entire UI,
这是我们整个用户界面,
Super simple,
超级简单,
All we need to do now is implement the guts of
现在我们需要做的就是实现的勇气
this controller right here,
这个控制器,
So let's go back to that,
让我们回到,
Here it is right here,
这是在这里,
Let's talk about the public API,
让我们来谈谈公共API,
I just really want to get in the habit of this,
我只是想的习惯,
Every time we introduce a new MVC, let's talk about it,
每次我们引入一个新的MVC,让我们谈论它,
its public API,
它的公共API,
So this SmashTweetersTableViewControl-
所以这SmashTweetersTableViewControl -
ler, really has two parts in its model,
l,真的有两个部分的模型,
One is, it needs to know the mention, the search term that
一个是,它需要知道提到,搜索词
its supposed to be showing the Tweeters for, so I'm gonna
它应该显示的高音,所以我要
have, I'll call it mention, which is just a string,
我叫它提到,这是一个字符串,
So that's part of its public model, and then,
这就是公共模型的一部分,然后,
what's the other part of its model?
另一部分的模型是什么?
The database,
数据库,
What it does is look up in the database and
它是在数据库中查找和
find tweeters who mention this in their tweets,
发现高音提到这个在他们的微博,
So it's gotta have an NSPersistentContainer here,
所以要有一个NSPersistentContainer这里,
By the way, some people, import CoreData,
顺便说一下,有些人,进口CoreData,
Instead of having the database represented in the public
而不是代表在公共的数据库
model here as a container,
模型是一个容器,
they might just pass the context only,
他们可以通过上下文,
If they pass the context only here though,
不过,如果他们只通过上下文这里
you can't do any background stuff,
你不能做任何背景的东西,
So I like to pass, pass the container here,
所以我想通过,通过这里的容器,
Plus, this whole thing is a UI element,
另外,这整个事情是一个UI元素,
so it wants to use a view context,
所以想要使用一个视图上下文,
No other context cuz it does its stuff all on the main
因为它没有其他上下文对最主要的东西
queue, it's a UI,
队列,这是一个用户界面,
So it's nice when you pass a container cuz you're gonna ask
所以很高兴当你通过容器因为你会问
for the view context and
的背景和观点
you know you're getting a main queue context,
你知道你得到一个主要的队列上下文,
Where if someone passes a context in here,
如果有人在这里,通过上下文
could be not be a main queue context, that could be bad,
可能不是一个主要的队列上下文,可能是坏的,
So I think a container is a good wrapper when you want to
所以我认为一个容器是一个很好的包装当你想
tell an MVC this is the database to use to do what you
告诉MVC是做你所使用的数据库
do, here it is,
在这里,
And sure we'll do our little trick here where we make
当然我们会做我们这里的小技巧
a default,
缺省情况下,
(UIApplication,shared,delegete as?
(UIApplication,共享,delegete吗?
AppDelegate)?,persistentConta- iner,
AppDelegate)?
You don't even really have to do this but we'll do it,
你甚至不需要这样做,但我们将这样做,
So that's basically our model and
这就是我们的模型
anytime our model changes,
在我们的模型的变化,
I'm gonna have a didSet here that updates my UI,
我要在这里有一个didSet更新我的界面,
We'll do the same thing,
我们会做同样的事情,
If I can select it,
如果我可以选择的话,
do the same thing with this guy right here,
与这个东西,做同样的事情
We need a private func to do that,
我们需要一个私有函数,
So this is our model, and it's UI updating,
这是我们的模型,它的UI更新
Now before I go implement this UI updating,
现在我去实现这个UI更新之前,
cuz it's pretty straightforward,
因为它很简单,
I'm gonna back to my SmashTweetTableViewController,
我要回到我的SmashTweetTableViewController,
the one that's gathering all the statistics,
收集所有的数据,
because that's also the one I'm segueing from,
因为这也是我segue从,
This smash, this one right here,
这个,这粉碎
Smash Tweet Table View Controller,
粉碎推表视图控制器,
I'm segueing from this to this using this button,
我从这segue使用这个按钮,
So that's where the prepare needs to be,
这是需要准备的,
So I'm gonna put the prepare in here for that,
所以我要把这里的准备,
So let's put the prepare down at the bottom here,
我们将准备在底部,
prepare (for segue:,
准备(:,
Here it is, Now,
在这里,现在,
I'm gonna go through this really fast because you guys
我要通过这个非常快,因为你们
surely know prepare (for segue: by now,
肯定知道准备(segue:到目前为止,
I mean to say if the segue:identifier is what
我的意思是说如果segue:标识符是什么
I said which is,
我是说,
and again I should make a constant here but for speed,
我应该做一个常数但是速度,
so this is Tweeters Mentioning Search Term,
这是高音提到搜索词,
that's what I called that segue,
这就是我称之为segue,
Then I'm going to get the destination,
然后我将得到目的地,
So that is a TweetersTableViewController =
这是一个TweetersTableViewController =
segues,destination as?
segues目的地,as ?
SmashTweetersTableViewControl- ler,
SmashTweetersTableViewControl - l,
And yeah, I could probably do ContentViewController here,
是的,我可以在这里做ContentViewController,
because if I had that extension in here, because
因为在这里,如果我有,扩展
maybe I want to put this in a split view someday and etc,
也许我想把它拆分视图有一天等,
But first time I won't do that,
但是第一次我不会这样做,
So now I've got the tweetersTVC,
所以现在我有tweetersTVC,
This is my TweetersTableViewController,
这是我的TweetersTableViewController,
I'm just gonna set its public API,
我要设置它的公共API,
TweetersTVC,mention,
TweetersTVC提到,
Mention equals my search term,
提到=我的搜索词,
This is the MVC where you type the text in so
这就是你输入MVC中的文本
it has search text,
搜索文本,
And then the tweetersTVC,container equals
然后tweetersTVC,容器=
my container,
我的容器,
I have the same one,
我也有同样的一个,
The tweeters MVC looking in the same database I'm
高音MVC相同的数据库我看
looking in,
在看,
So here I am actually setting this thing,
所以我在这里实际上设置这个东西,
We got an error here, what is it?
我们这里有一个错误,它是什么?
Tweeters, okay,
Tweeters,好吧,
All right, so I'm just setting my public model of
好吧,我只是设置的公共模型
my Tweeters, not Tweet, TweetersTableViewController,
我的推特,不是微博,TweetersTableViewController
SImple enough,
很简单,
All right, now that we are all ready to segue to this nice
好吧,既然我们都准备segue这个不错
SmashTableViewController, how do we update its UI?
SmashTableViewController,我们如何更新它的UI ?
How do we get it to look in CoreData,
我们如何让它看CoreData,
find the Twitter users that have tweeted something that
找到的Twitter用户在推特上的东西
matches this mention and show it?
匹配这提及并展示吗?
Well, there's really,
有真的,
we're gonna use NS Fetched Results Controller, of course,
我们将使用NS控制器获取结果,当然,
that's the main deal here,
这是这里的主要协议,
And what are the pieces we need to do?
件我们需要做的是什么?
This was the last slide from the last lecture,
这是上节课的最后一张幻灯片,
I hope you all remember it, it was very recent,
我希望你们记住它,它很近,
First thing is we have to have this table-view controller
第一件事是我们必须有这个表格视图控制器
be an NS-fetched-result-controller
是一个NS-fetched-result-controller
If you're going to use a fetched results controller
如果你想使用一个控制器获取结果
delegate,
委托,
your table needs to be the delegate of that fetched
你的表需要获取的委托
controller, and I told you I was going to help you out with
控制器,我告诉过你我要帮助你
that and provide that code and sure enough I am,
,并提供代码,果然,我
It's right here,
就在这里,
I'm gonna drag it in somewhere, copy it in, yes,
我要把它拖到某处,复制它,是的,
All right, and let's take a look at it, here it is,
好吧,让我们看看,在这里,
FetchedResultsTableViewContro- ller,
FetchedResultsTableViewContro——噢,
You can see that it is a subclass of
你可以看到它的子类
UITableViewController that implements the
UITableViewController实现
NSFetchedResultsControllerDel- egate protocol,
NSFetchedResultsControllerDel egate协议,
So these are the methods right here in our protocol,
所以这些方法在我们的协议,
there are four of them,
有四个,
You can see that it is just using table view methods
你可以看到它是使用表格视图的方法
to update the table,
更新表,
These controller methods get called whenever the NS
这些控制器方法被调用时NS
Fetched Result Controller notices the database change
获取结果控制器通知数据库变更
in a way that would affect the NS Fetched Result,
在某种程度上影响NS获取结果,
So this is the magic that makes your table
这是一个神奇的让你的表
automatically update when the database changes,
自动更新数据库时的变化,
You don't have to do anything, it just automatically updates,
你不需要做任何事情,它就自动更新,
It's because of this delegate,
因为这个委托的,
Now, for our thing to work we need to be a subclass of this,
现在,我们需要对我们的工作的一个子类,
so that we inherit all this stuff,
这样我们继承这些东西,
we're just going to go back to our smashTweeters here and
我们将回到我们的smashTweeters这里
So that's easy,
这很简单,
instead of being a UITableViewController,
而不是一个UITableViewController,
I'm gonna be a FetchedResultsTableViewContro-
我要一个FetchedResultsTableViewContro -
ller, simple,
简单、默勒
So, that's the easy way to become
所以,这是最简单的方式
a FetchedResultsController delegate,
一个,FetchedResultsController委托,
Now, what was the next thing we need to do?
现在,接下来我们需要做的是什么?
We have to implement all of our UITableViewDataSource
我们要实现我们所有的需要
Methods using a fetchedResultsController,
方法使用,fetchedResultsController,
So there's two parts to that,
有两个部分,
One is we need to create a var, which is
一个是我们需要创建一个var,
a fetchedResultsController controller,
,fetchedResultsController控制器,
It's going to be a type NSFetchedResultsController,
这将是一种NSFetchedResultsController,
It's FetchResultsController that fetches tweeter users,
FetchResultsController获取的推特用户,
So FetchResultsController is also generic type and
所以FetchResultsController也是泛型类型
you have to say what kind of thing does it fetch?
你说什么东西卖吗?
So I've got this var, how do I implement all
所以我有这个var,如何实现
those UI table of your data source methods as well?
这些UI数据源表方法吗?
Well, I can type them all in but you know what,
好吧,我可以输入他们所有人,但你知道吗,
it's exactly the same in every single to every single time
在每一个完全相同的每一次
you implement one of these the code is exactly the same
实现一个完全相同的代码
because fetchedResultsController
因为,fetchedResultsController
always answers those questions in exactly the same way,
总是以完全相同的方式回答这些问题,
So you could copy and
所以你可以复制和
paste it from some other half that you've done or
粘贴在其他一些你所做的一半
you could use this little beauty that I've created for
你可以用这个小美女,我创建了
you right here, another little thing you can drag in,
你在这里,另一个小东西你可以拖拽,
which we'll take a look,
我们会看一看,
Copy that, and this is an extension
复制,这是一个扩展
that you can extend your class,
你能扩展你的类,
So in this case,
所以在这种情况下,
it's our smash tweeters tableviewController,
这是我们粉碎,高音表
And in this extension,
在这个扩展,
it adds all the UI tableview data source methods,
它增加了所有uitableview数据源方法,
See,
看到的,
And implements them in terms of your
和你的来实现
fetchresultscontroller,
Now, this extension will not compile if you do not have
现在,这个扩展将不会编译如果你没有
a fetch results controller because extensions can't add
获取结果控制器,因为扩展不能添加
any storage themselves so you have to have the storage be in
任何存储自己所以你需要存储
your class but this class does have fetch result controller,
你的类,但这类获取结果控制器,
Now, the one thing it doesn't implement here though is
现在,这里是没有实现
cellForRowAt cuz cellForRowAt add is specific to whatever
cellForRowAt因为cellForRowAt添加特定于任何
data you're showing in the table but
但你的数据显示在表
even cellForRowAt, if we go back here and do cellForRowAt,
即使cellForRowAt,如果我们回到这里,做cellForRowAt,
let's do that so cellForRowAt index path more with,
做一下所以cellForRowAt索引路径,
And, of course, we know how to do that right,
当然,我们知道怎么做吧,
let the cell equal to tableView deque this one,
让细胞等于tableView双端队列,
and the Identifier was "TwitterUser Cell" I believe,
标识符是“TwitterUser单元”我相信,
correct me if I'm wrong,
纠正我如果我错了,
And we want IndexPath there, so I got the cell, and
我们希望IndexPath那里,所以我得到了细胞,
we return the cell,
我们返回的细胞,
And in between,
在之间,
I need to load the cell up with its various information,
我需要负载细胞和它的各种信息,
Now we set our cell to be, if you remember,
现在我们组细胞,如果你还记得,
a Subtitle cell, right?
一个副标题细胞,对吧?
This is a Subtitle cell,
这是一个副标题细胞,
So we can set its TextLabel and its detailTextLabel,
所以我们可以设置其TextLabel及其detailTextLabel
So let's just start with just the TextLabel,
让我们开始TextLabel,
So I wanna set the cell,textLabels Text,
我想设置单元,textLabels文本,
basically equal to the twitter uses handle,
基本上等于twitter使用句柄,
But I have to get the twitter user that's in this row,
但是我必须让twitter用户在这一行,
Okay, how do I find the twitter user
好了,我怎么找到twitter用户
that's in the role?
的作用?
I'm gonna ask my fetch results controller,
我要问一下我取回结果控制器,
Let the twitter user in this role,
让这个角色的twitter用户,
in this row, equal my fetch results controller
在这一行,等于我取回结果控制器
which might be null cuz it's an optional,
这可能是零因为它是一个可选的,
Object(at: indexPath),
对象(:indexPath),
And since this could be nil because this could be nil
因为这可能是零,因为这可能是零
right here let's do if let, then we will update our cell,
如果让我们做,然后我们将更新我们的细胞,
Now if we didn't have a fetchedResultsController,
如果我们没有,fetchedResultsController,
by the way, if this were nil, our number of rows and
顺便说一下,如果这是零,我们的行数
sections would be zero all the time,
部分将是零,
This would never be called,
这永远不会被称为,
So we can even put an exclamation point here,
所以我们甚至可以把感叹号,
And maybe we should put an exclamation point here
也许我们应该把一个感叹号
because this should never be called if this is nil,
因为这个不应该被称为如果这是零,
But anyway, so it's this very simple method, object)at:,
但无论如何,这是非常简单的方法,对象):
is gonna return you the thing of the type
你会返回类型的东西吗
that it's controlling, which is Twitter user,
它的控制,这是Twitter用户,
And if we look at the type here,
如果我们看看类型,
you can see that's a Twitter user that goes at this
你可以看到这是一个Twitter用户
index path,
索引路径,
So that row and that section,
这一行和这部分,
So it could not be easier,
所以它不能简单,
And now we can just, in here, update whatever you or
现在我们可以,在这里,不管你或更新
I want, no matter how complicated it is,
我希望,不管它有多复杂,
We've got the Twitter user that's showing there, so
我们有显示的Twitter用户,所以
we can his handle, his username, whatever else,
我们可以处理,用户名,其他,
We wanna get on him and put it in there,
我们想要在他身上,把它放在那里,
Everybody got that?
大家都明白了吗?
Super simple, and
超级简单,
yes it is super simple that's what's great about in fetch
是的它是超级简单,就是伟大的取回
results controller is that really the amount of code we
结果控制器是我们真正的代码数量
actually had to write here is absolutely tiny,
有写在这里绝对是小,
Now, there is one piece left which is update UI so
现在,还有一块是更新UI
when someone sets our mention or sets our database,
当有人集我们提到或设置数据库,
we need to create a fetch results controller, obviously,
我们需要创建一个控制器获取结果,显然,
Just can't be nil all the time,
不能是零,
we actually have to create one and we're just gonna say,
我们必须创建一个和我们只是想说,
fetchResultsController = a new
fetchResultsController =一个新的
NSFetchedResultsController, which is for Twitter users,
NSFetchedResultsController,Twitter用户,
And we will use this constructor right here,
我们将使用这个构造函数,
I'll go ahead and separate this out so
我要独立出来
you can see a little better what the arguments are,
你可以看到一个更好的理由是什么,
Let me see from this slide as well,
让我看看从这张幻灯片,
So what are the four things we need?
那么我们需要的四件事是什么呢?
We need a request, I'll make a request,
我们需要一个请求,我将做一个请求,
We need a context, I'll make a context,
我们需要一个环境,我将做一个背景下,
We need the name of the var in TwitterUser,
我们需要在TwitterUser var的名称,
that says this section title,
说本节标题,
Well, we don't have any sections all our Twitter users
好吧,我们没有任何部分我们所有的Twitter用户
are gonna be shown in one big like long list,
会显示在一个大长串,
so that's nil and we won't cache our results,
这是零,我们不会缓存结果,
Although we could, because we're never gonna change this
虽然我们可以,因为我们不会改变这一现状
request--well, actually that's not true,
请求,其实那不是真的,
We could change this because someone might
我们可以改变这个,因为有人会
bring up this MVC and then change the mention and
把这MVC然后改变提及
that would be changing the request to look for different
这将是改变请求不同
twitter users so it's better not to catch this beside
twitter用户最好不要抓这个旁边
the results are hopefully gonna be fairly small,
希望结果会是相当小的,
So I have to do a request in context here,
所以我要做一个请求上下文,
Let's do context first,
让我们先做背景,
I'm gonna say if I can let my context equal my containers
我想说如果我可以让我的上下文相同的容器中
View context,
视图的背景下,
Now, this is very important right here to use
现在,这是非常重要的
view context because this is a Ui thing,
视图上下文Ui的事情,因为这是一个
And this fetch results controller is gonna be working
这取结果控制器会工作
with our table view controller, that's all UI so
与我们的表格视图控制器,这是所有UI
we wanna do this all in the main queue,
我们想在主队列做这一切,
So, you have to use view context,
所以,你必须使用视图上下文,
You cannot do that background thing
你不能这样做背景
to create your FetchResultController,
创建你的FetchResultController,
All right, so all that leaves is this request here so
好吧,这是所有的叶子请求这里
I'm gonna let the request it's obviously going to
我要让它显然会请求
be an NSFetchRequest for Twitter users,
是一个NSFetchRequest Twitter用户,
And we use this nice convenience thing here
我们使用这个方便的事情
TwitterUser,FetchRequest and so what does our request need?
TwitterUser,FetchRequest和我们的要求需要什么?
Well, our request needs sort descriptors, so
嗯,我们的要求需要描述符,所以
we're gonna have to have some array of sort descriptors,
我们要有一系列的描述符,
Our request also needs a predicate,
我们的要求也需要一个谓词,
Predicate,
谓词,
Whoops, gotta get format right here, this one,
哎呀,这里得格式,这一个,
We're gonna have to have some format string there, and
我们会有一些格式字符串,和
then some args for the percent at signs,
然后一些args的百分比的迹象,
So let's do this sort descriptor first,
让我们先做这类描述符,
We're looking for all the Twitter users who have tweeted
我们正在寻找所有的Twitter用户
something that mentioned that search for a minute,
提到搜索一下,
Let's order them by their handle, at sign whatever,
我们命令他们处理,在任何迹象,
So all we need to do then is say, NSSortDescriptor with and
那么我们需要做的是说,NSSortDescriptor和
we'll use the one with the key,
我们将使用的关键,
It's not, it's going to make me type it, arg,
它不是,它会让我输入,参数,
So we'll do the key handle and we'll do ascending true,
所以我们要做的关键处理,我们会提升真的,
That's good enough, we'll just have it sort however it sorts,
那已经足够好了,我们就把它但是它,
We'll come back to sorting later and look at it,
我们将回到排序后,看着它,
We only need one sort descriptor we're not gonna
我们只需要一个描述符我们不会
sort by the a handle and
一个句柄和排序
then subsort by something else because the handle will be
然后由其他东西,因为subsort处理
sufficient sorting in there, and what about our predicate?
足够的排序,和我们的谓语呢?
What tweeter users are we looking for here?
推特用户我们在这里找什么?
This is really the key to making anything work and for
这是真正的关键和任何工作
your homework by the way,
顺便说一下,你的家庭作业
really this homework it's not a lot of programming,
真的这作业不是很多编程,
It's a lot of thinking,
这是一个很多思考,
Especially designing your schema so
特别是设计模式
that this line of code right here is really simple,
这行代码是很简单的,
If you design your schema properly you can make
如果你正确你可以设计你的模式
this quite simple,
这很简单,
It's all about thinking about what am I actually showing,
其实都是想我展示,
and how do I calculate what those things are,
和我如何计算这些东西是什么,
In this case I'm showing all the Twitter users,
在这种情况下我给所有的Twitter用户,
Any of the twitter users here whose tweets,
这里的twitter用户的微博,
the text in their tweets actually, contains, and
文本在他们的微博,包含,
we'll go case insensitively, that search term,
我们将区分大小写,搜索词,
Our mention,
我们提到,
Which is optional, so we'd better unwrap,
这是可选的,所以我们最好打开,
And if I'm gonna unwrap this forcibly,
如果我要强行打开,
I'm actually going to check to make sure it's not nil,
我要检查,以确保它不是零,
Just to be careful there,
只是要小心,
So this is the predicate we want,
这是我们想要的谓词,
We want any Twitter user,
我们希望任何Twitter用户,
Because we're looking for Twitter users,
因为我们正在寻找Twitter用户,
any Twitter user who's tweets, any of their tweets,
任何Twitter用户的微博,他们的微博,
texts contains this mention,
文本包含这个提到,
This is actually,
这是,
I probably said that a little bit wrong there,
我可能说错了,一点
We're looking for any Twitter user who have any
我们正在寻找任何有Twitter用户
of it's tweets text contains this mention,
推文的文本包含这个提到,
Off of any, means here, anything, any of the tweets
的,意味着在这里,任何东西,任何的tweet
texts contains this, then show this twitter user here,
文本包含这个,那么显示这里的twitter用户,
Everybody got all that?
每个人都有吗?
So now, I got my fetch request controller,
所以现在,我取回请求控制器,
remember the only two things I need to do now is to
记得唯一我现在需要做的是两件事
try to have my fetched results controller perform this fetch,
试图让我获取结果控制器执行此取回,
okay that can throw, so that's why we're trying there,
能把好了,这就是为什么我们正在那里,
And we've got to tell our table view, time to go
我们要告诉我们的表视图,时间去
call all of your UI table view data source methods, and
叫你所有的UI数据源表视图方法,和
we know whose going to answer that,
我们知道,要回答这个问题,
that extension that we have there,
我们有,扩展,
And it's going to ask fetched results controller for
这是要问控制器获取结果
all the information it needs,
所需的所有信息,
By the way, notice I made this public, (internal, basically),
顺便说一下,请注意我做了这个,(内部,基本上),
That's because I put that extension over here
那是因为我把它扩展
in a different file and
在一个不同的文件
it wouldn't be a receive this otherwise,
它不会收到这否则,
So, if you wanna make this var private,
所以,如果你想让这个var私人,
which is not a bad idea, actually,
这不是一个坏主意,实际上,
In a MVC that is using a fetchedResultsController,
使用,fetchedResultsController MVC中,
making its controller public is kinda opening up
使其控制器公众开放
the internal guts of it,
它的内部结构,
If you wanna make this private, then you would just
如果你想让这个私人的,那么你就会
put this extension at the bottom of the file,
把这个扩展在文件的底部,
in the same file,
在相同的文件,
That way they you would be able to see it,
这样你能看到它,
Hopefully we've remembered everything,
希望我们记得一切,
let's go give this a try,
让我们去做这个实验,
Let's go here #stanford again,
让我们再#斯坦福大学,
Now I'm gonna press Tweeters,
现在我要按推特,
And it's going to segue to this new MVC that
它将继续这个新MVC
will hopefully show us a list of all the people who
希望给我们所有的人的列表吗
have tweeted here,
这里有推特,
And sure enough, there it is,
果然,就在那里。
These are all the people who have tweeted one of
这些都是推的人之一
the tweets that was found by that search team,
搜索团队的微博发现,
Search term #stanford,
搜索词#斯坦福大学,
It even has that listed at the top, which is kinda cool,
它甚至有上市顶部,有点酷,
because that's the same as the back button here,
因为这是一样的后退按钮,
Now, one thing I don't like about this,
现在,有一件事我不喜欢,
a couple of things, one, subtitle,
几件事情,1、副标题,
Okay that's no good,
好,不好,
we could put something better there like,
我们可以把更好的东西,
maybe we could put how many tweets they've tweeted
也许我们可以把多少推他们推
that match that search term, that'd be cool,
搜索词的匹配,会很酷,
And then, the other thing is the order its in,
然后,另一件事是订单,
look at this, all the capital letter's first and
看看这个,所有的大写字母的第一个
then all the lowercase letters after it,
之后所有的小写字母,
I want it all to be alphabetical case insensitive,
我想要所有的字母不区分大小写,
And like that,
像这样,
so let's fix those things,
所以让我们解决这些事情,
So the case insensitive is just a matter of sorting,
因此,不分大小写只是一个排序的问题,
We're sorting there and it's sorting by some default,
我们整理的一些默认的排序,
while the default is obviously case sensitive search and
在默认搜索,显然是大小写敏感的
we don't want that,
我们不希望这样,
So, this is where this sorting selector comes in,
所以,这就是这个排序选择器,
And we just say #selector and it's gotta be an NSString
我们只是说#选择器要NSString
selector because this is an NSString field,
选择器,因为这是一个NSString领域,
And there's quite a few of them,
还有很多,
if you type compare, you'll get to see what they are,
如果你类型比较,你就会看到它们是什么,
So, there's a localizedCaseInsensitive,
所以,有一个localizedCaseInsensitive,
this kind of thing, so, let's try CaseInsensitive,
这种事情,所以,让我们尝试CaseInsensitive,
Let's do localized case insensitive compare,
让我们做本地化不分大小写比较,
So that's case insensitive, and using the user's local
这是不分大小写,并使用用户的地方
language to know what goes where, what the ordering is,
语言知道了,定是什么,
So that's a pretty good one,
这是一个很好的一个,
to use localized case insensitive compare,
使用局部不分大小写比较,
So that's all we need to do to the case sensitivity,
这就是我们要做的大小写敏感性,
that was really easy,
这真的很容易,
How about this thing of having the cells detail text label?
这事怎么样的细胞详细文本标签吗?
Have the twitter account,
twitter帐户,
basically the account of tweet,
基本上twitter的帐户,
So I'm gonna say this equals twitter tweet count,
所以我会说,这等于twitter微博数,
Tweet and let's even be nice here and put an s if it's one,
微博让我们即使在这里很好,把一个年代如果是一个,
Count equals one,
数等于1,
Then we'll put an s on the end otherwise we're nothing,
然后我们会把一个年代的结束,否则我们什么都没有,
Okay, every one see what I did there?
好的,每一个看到我做了什么?
So it will take one tweet,
所以需要一个微博,
What else do we need to do here?
我们还需要做什么吗?
We'll do this,
我们会这样做,
All right, so I just want to make it look nice,
好吧,我只是想让它看起来不错,
One tweet, two tweets, zero tweets,
一个微博,两个微博,微博,零
How do I get this tweet count right here and
我怎么得到这个tweet计数和
let tweet count equal something?
让微博数等于什么?
And to do this, I'm going to do a little quick
要做到这一点,我要做的有点快
fast type code, because we're getting close to the end here,
快速类型代码,因为我们这里接近结束时,
I have a method here called tweet count,
我在这里有一个方法叫做微博数,
with mention by right here,
提到的在这里,
And let's look at this method and how this works,
让我们看看这个方法,这是如何工作的,
So this is gonna give the tweetCountWithMentionBy
这是要给tweetCountWithMentionBy
this twitterUser, the twitterUser that we got from
我们从这个twitterUser twitterUser
our fetchResultsController,
我们的fetchResultsController,
It's gonna give us the tweetCount,
它会给我们tweetCount,
And the way it's work is it's gonna create a fetch
和它的工作是要创建一个取回
for tweet,
微博,
So here even in the middle of my cellForRowAtIndexPath,
这甚至在半夜我cellForRowAtIndexPath,
I'm making a request perfectly valid to go to a fetch
我正在做一个请求完全有效去取回
request right in the middle here to find some information,
请求在这里找到一些信息,
So here I'm fetching for Tweets this time,
这里我抓取微博这一次,
cause I wanna count the number of Tweets this Twitter user
因为我想数一数这个Twitter用户的tweet
has Tweeted with that so sure,
推了,那么肯定,
And the predicate is,
谓词是,
"tell me all the Tweets who's text contains that mention",
“告诉我所有的消息文本包含提及是谁”,
And who's Tweeter is this Twitter user?
和推特这是Twitter用户是谁?
Mention and a twitterUser,
提到twitterUser,
And I'm gonna go ahead and force unwrap that,
我要和力打开,
because, boy if I get all the way down to here,
因为,男孩如果我一直到在这里,
surely the mention is not nil,
当然提到不是零,
And then I'm going to return,
然后我要返回,
I'm going to use the same context the twitterUser is in,
我将使用相同的上下文twitterUser在,
hopefully that's a view context,
希望这是一个视图上下文,
And I'm going to count, use that count thing for
我要统计,使用计数的事情
that request,
请求,
And if that fails for some reason,
如果由于某种原因失败时,
I'm gonna say 0 tweets,
我会说0条,
Have you got that?
你明白我的意思吗?
So let's go
所以让我们去
take a look,
看一看,
Right, #stanford,
#斯坦福大学,
Right, here it is,
在这里,
Tweeters, look at that, not 1 tweet, 37 tweets from MEC30,
高音,你看那个,不是1条推特,从MEC30 37 tweet,
Let's go see if we can find MEC30 in here,
让我们去看看我们是否能找到MEC30在这里,
Sure, there's one my MEC30, another one, sure enough,
当然,有一个我MEC30,另一个,果然,
Look at this ME, what the?
看这我,什么?
Okay, what if I decide I don't want MEC30 in there anymore,
好吧,如果我决定我不想MEC30在那里了,
I don't like, this guy is a spammer or something,
我不喜欢,这个人是一个垃圾邮件发送者,
I don't know what his problem is,
我不知道他的问题是什么,
But I don't want him in there,
但我不希望他在那里,
Well, I can go back here and change my predicate right here
好了,我可以回到这里,改变我的谓词
to say, I want all the tweets that have that,
说,我想要的所有微博,
But I don't want ones where the handle of that guy, let's
但我不希望处理的那个家伙,我们
say it even begins with, just to be kind of interesting MEC,
说它甚至开始,就有点有趣的MEC,
What was it?
是什么?
MEC, we'll say,
MEC,我们会说,
And we can't put this literal in here, so
我们不能把这个文字在这里,
we have to say %@ and then we put the MEC on the outside,
我们不得不说% @然后我们把MEC在外面,
So let's see
让我们看看
if that got rid
如果去掉
of Mr, MEC,
MEC先生,
He gone!
他不见了!
Got that spammer out of there,
明白了垃圾信息散布者,
No questions?
没有问题吗?
Yes? Question?
是吗?
Yeah, so the question is, are the tweets in the database,
是的,问题是,数据库中的信息,
do they stay in there for run to run?
他们呆在那里跑,跑吗?
And the answer is absolutely,
答案是绝对的,
that's one, core data is kinda all about,
这是一个核心数据是有点,
There's a permanent database,
有一个永久的数据库,
So all those tweets, those #stanford tweets in there,
所以所有这些推文,那些#斯坦福微博,
if we go back and run again,
如果我们回去再次运行,
And search for #stanford,
和搜索#斯坦福大学,
If there have, you know,
如果有,你知道,
been some tweets since then they'll be added,
一些twitter之后他们会被添加,
But every single tweet we ever got is still
但每一个微博我们仍了
going to be in here,
在这里,
So you can see this list actually got slightly longer,
所以你可以看到这个列表实际上有稍微长一点,
a few tweets were in there, but they're all in there,
几个微博都在那里,但他们都在那里呢,
we're unique-ing them so it's not adding them over and over,
我们unique-ing他们这不是增加他们一遍又一遍,
And you gotta be careful to do that on your homework,
你要小心地做你的家庭作业,
Don't add them over and over,
不要把它们一遍又一遍,
But yeah, that CoreData database is there,
但是是的,CoreData数据库,
By the way, I'm gonna show you a trick,
顺便说一下,我要告诉你一个窍门,
We just enough time to show you something's really cool,
我们只是足够的时间向你展示一些很酷,
What if you want to delete your database?
如果你想删除数据库呢?
Okay, now there's two reasons you wanna,
好了,现在有两个原因你想,
might wanna delete your database,
可能想删除数据库,
One, you wanna clear the data out cuz you wanna get a fresh
一个,你想要清除数据因为你想要一个新鲜
set so you can see if things are working,
所以你可以看到如果事情工作,
And number two, you might change your data model,
第二,你可能会改变你的数据模型,
If I go back here and I go to my data model here and
如果我回到这里,我去和我的数据模型
I add some attributes or add an entity,
我添加一些属性或添加一个实体,
then my app will no longer run on that device or
然后我的设备或应用程序将不再运行
on the simulator cuz it'll say your data model doesn't match
模拟器上因为它会说你的数据模型不匹配
the data that's already on this device,
已经在这个设备的数据,
So here's the magic to get rid of, it's not very magical,
这是魔法摆脱,它不是很神奇,
Is on your device, or
在你的设备上,还是
on the simulator, you go to the home button right here and
模拟器,按钮在这里和你去家里
you press and hold to make the things jiggle,
你按住摇晃的东西,
You all know about that?
你们都知道吗?
It's how you delete apps,
这是你如何删除应用程序,
And just delete your app,
删除你的应用,
And when you delete your app, your core data goes with it,
当你删除你的应用,你的核心数据,
And now when you run the next time, you're gonna run,
现在,当您运行下次,你要跑,
it's gonna be a fresh database,
它会是一个新的数据库,
it will have the new data model etc,
它将有新的数据模型等,
So I'm very glad you asked that,
我很高兴你问,
really important to know how to clear out your database,
真正重要的知道如何清理你的数据库,
Now if we do #trump or something,
如果我们做#特朗普,
see it's even asking me again, do I wanna allow it?
再次见到甚至问我,我想让它吗?
And I do,
我做的,
All right, that is it,
好吧,就是这样,
I will see you next Wednesday after you turn in your
下周三我将见到你在你在你转
homework and
作业,
we'll learn all about the final project in Autolayout,
我们将学习所有关于自动布局,最终项目的
For more, please visit us at stanford,edu,
更多信息,请访问我们的斯坦福大学edu,